<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Releases on Regolith Desktop</title><link>https://regolith-desktop.com/docs/reference/Releases/</link><description>Recent content in Releases on Regolith Desktop</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><atom:link href="https://regolith-desktop.com/docs/reference/Releases/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>3.0 Release Notes</title><link>https://regolith-desktop.com/docs/reference/Releases/regolith-3.0-release-notes/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://regolith-desktop.com/docs/reference/Releases/regolith-3.0-release-notes/</guid><description>Regolith 3.0 is in pre-release. This document currently describes beta 1 and will be updated up to the final release once available. For wayland support, the XResource key names were changed as to not be tied to i3-wm. See the migration guide below for details on how to update customizations. Regolith 3.0 is a major release focusing on a new Wayland-based session, Debian 12, and Ubuntu 23.04 support.</description></item><item><title>2.2 Release Notes</title><link>https://regolith-desktop.com/docs/reference/Releases/regolith-2.2-release-notes/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://regolith-desktop.com/docs/reference/Releases/regolith-2.2-release-notes/</guid><description>Regolith 2.2 is a minor release focusing on bug fixes and Ubuntu 22.10 support.
New Features # Ubuntu 22.10 (kinetic) support Wallpaper may be changed in regolith-control-center on Ubuntu Kinetic and Debian Bookworm. Bug Fixes # i3-swap-focus now available as released in 2.1 Numerous fixes and polish added to ilia Known Issues # No localization for ilia Changelog Delta from Regolith Desktop 2.</description></item><item><title>2.1 Release Notes</title><link>https://regolith-desktop.com/docs/reference/Releases/regolith-2.1-release-notes/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://regolith-desktop.com/docs/reference/Releases/regolith-2.1-release-notes/</guid><description>Regolith 2.1 is a minor release including several improvements, bug fixes, and optimizations.
New Features # Regolith Linux 2.1 ISOs (based from Ubuntu 22.04) Looks dracula, ayu, ayu-dark, ayu-mirage, i3-default, and lascaille added Looks can be loaded from user directories (~/.config/regolith2/looks) i3-swap-focus is now available. Navigate to last window with keybinding &amp;lt;super&amp;gt; . Bug Fixes # Ilia&amp;rsquo;s file search dialog was broken on Jammy, this has been fixed PtrSc hotkeys working as in 1.</description></item><item><title>2.0 Release Notes</title><link>https://regolith-desktop.com/docs/reference/Releases/regolith-2.0-release-notes/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://regolith-desktop.com/docs/reference/Releases/regolith-2.0-release-notes/</guid><description>Regolith 2.0 is a major release with some breaking changes to looks and i3 configuration, and includes several improvements and optimizations.
New Features # Adding Debian Bullseye to the list of supported OS&amp;rsquo;s including Ubuntu Focal and Jammy. The desktop UI component rofi was replaced with desktop executor designed specifically for Regolith: ilia. The desktop UI component gnome-control-center was replaced with a settings app designed specifically for Regolith: regolith-control-center.</description></item><item><title>1.6 Release Notes</title><link>https://regolith-desktop.com/docs/reference/Releases/regolith-1.6.0-release-notes/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://regolith-desktop.com/docs/reference/Releases/regolith-1.6.0-release-notes/</guid><description>Regolith R1.6 is a feature release which includes several improvements and optimizations. Regolith 1.6&amp;rsquo;s primary feature is a return of the ISO installation method.
Features # Feature Screenshot Description Return of Regolith Linux ISO Up to Regolith 1.4.1, we hand-built each ISO for major version releases. This became too brittle and time intensive, and so work began on build automation to generate the ISO.</description></item><item><title>1.5.3 Release Notes</title><link>https://regolith-desktop.com/docs/reference/Releases/regolith-1.5.3-release-notes/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://regolith-desktop.com/docs/reference/Releases/regolith-1.5.3-release-notes/</guid><description>Regolith 1.5.3 is a bug fix release. The following list contains brief descriptions of fixes and updates per package since the Regolith 1.5.2 release:
Release Notes for i3xrocks # i3xrocks (1.3.5-1) bionic; urgency=medium
[ Ken Gilmer ]
Do not print system file error if user files do not exist. Addresses https://github.com/regolith-linux/regolith-i3xrocks-config/issues/114. Release Notes for regolith-desktop # regolith-desktop (2.111-1bionic) bionic; urgency=medium
[ Ken Gilmer ]
Move from i3xrocks-todo to regolith-todo to address https://github.</description></item><item><title>1.5.2 Release Notes</title><link>https://regolith-desktop.com/docs/reference/Releases/regolith-1.5.2-release-notes/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://regolith-desktop.com/docs/reference/Releases/regolith-1.5.2-release-notes/</guid><description>Regolith 1.5.2 is a bug fix release. The following list contains brief descriptions of fixes and updates per package since the Regolith 1.5.1 release:
Release Notes for regolith-compositor-picom-glx # Remove manual fade flag passed to compositor in favor of specification in config file. Allows users to specify fade parameters via config file. Release Notes for regolith-ftue # Check update flag before changing gnome-terminal. Allows users to turn gnome-terminal profile generation off.</description></item><item><title>1.5.1 Release Notes</title><link>https://regolith-desktop.com/docs/reference/Releases/regolith-1.5.1-release-notes/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://regolith-desktop.com/docs/reference/Releases/regolith-1.5.1-release-notes/</guid><description>Regolith 1.5.1 is a bug fix release. The following list contains brief descriptions of fixes and updates per package since the Regolith 1.5 release:
Release Notes for i3-next-workspace # Initial copy from regolith-i3xrocks-config. Release Notes for regolith-compositor-picom-glx # Add xrender-sync-fence for better support of nvidia systems. Release Notes for regolith-default-settings # Add breaks declaration to deal w/ ISO upgrade issue Release Notes for regolith-desktop # ship version file with all desktop variants Update version to 1.</description></item><item><title>1.5 Release Notes</title><link>https://regolith-desktop.com/docs/reference/Releases/regolith-1.5-release-notes/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://regolith-desktop.com/docs/reference/Releases/regolith-1.5-release-notes/</guid><description>Regolith R1.5 is a feature release which includes several improvements and optimizations. To summarize, Regolith 1.5 ships simpler workspace management, a Rofi-based Look switcher, and numerous internal optimizations and cleanup. Read below for more details.
Features # Feature Screenshot Description Next Free Workspace A typical part of managing workspaces in an i3-based desktop is moving to unused workspaces and then loading some applications.</description></item><item><title>1.4.1 Release Notes</title><link>https://regolith-desktop.com/docs/reference/Releases/regolith-1.4.1-release-notes/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://regolith-desktop.com/docs/reference/Releases/regolith-1.4.1-release-notes/</guid><description>Regolith R1.4.1 is a fast follow up to 1.4 that fixes a few serious bugs, detailed on the mailing list. In addition to the package updates, a new boot animation is provided by the package plymouth-theme-regolith that is installed by default on the ISO. The ISO also now excludes a deprecated touchpad driver that was conflicting with Settings. Existing PPA-based installations can simply get the updates via their typical package update process.</description></item><item><title>1.4 Release Notes</title><link>https://regolith-desktop.com/docs/reference/Releases/regolith-1.4-release-notes/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://regolith-desktop.com/docs/reference/Releases/regolith-1.4-release-notes/</guid><description>Regolith R1.4 is a major feature release which includes several improvements and optimizations. Regolith is now smaller and more efficient. The ISO-based installer is now based from the Xubuntu image, and moves from the gdm3 display manager to LightDM. This allows for less resource consumption at runtime and dramatically smaller download size1. A new look, lascaille and file search dialog round out the major new features. Read below for more details.</description></item><item><title>1.3.1 Release Notes</title><link>https://regolith-desktop.com/docs/reference/Releases/regolith-1.3.1-release-notes/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://regolith-desktop.com/docs/reference/Releases/regolith-1.3.1-release-notes/</guid><description>R1.3.1 is a quick followup to R1.3 that adds polish and usability features. Headlining features include a more concise way of overriding Xresource defaults and several enhancements to the Remontoire keybinding viewer.
If you maintain your own i3 config file, note that the copy shipped in Regolith 1.3.1 has changed in that the comment format has been modified to be readable by Remontoire (example). Without updating your copy i3 config comments, you will not see any keybindings.</description></item><item><title>1.3 Release Notes</title><link>https://regolith-desktop.com/docs/reference/Releases/regolith-1.3-release-notes/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://regolith-desktop.com/docs/reference/Releases/regolith-1.3-release-notes/</guid><description>Following R1.2, the 1.3 release focused on usability issues reported by users and a continuing refinement of the desktop environment in general, with a focus on making the system easier for those inexperienced with tiling window managers.
Features # Feature Screenshot Description Cahuella GTK Theme A new GTK theme was created for Regolith that more closely follows the standard GNOME theme, Adwaita.</description></item></channel></rss>