<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Introduction on Regolith Desktop</title><link>https://regolith-desktop.com/</link><description>Recent content in Introduction on Regolith Desktop</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><atom:link href="https://regolith-desktop.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>First Launch</title><link>https://regolith-desktop.com/docs/using-regolith/first-launch/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://regolith-desktop.com/docs/using-regolith/first-launch/</guid><description>First Launch # Regolith&amp;rsquo;s default interface lacks any visual hint as to how to launch applications or perform other common tasks. This can make the first time experience a bit confusing. However using the Regolith interface is relatively simple by only committing the following two keybindings to memory:
Action Keybinding Purpose Keybinding Viewer super shift ? View and execute available keybindings App Launcher super space Launch a desktop application The Super Key # Most keybindings you&amp;rsquo;ll be using with Regolith start with the super key.</description></item><item><title>Customize i3 Configuration</title><link>https://regolith-desktop.com/docs/howtos/customize-i3-configuration/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://regolith-desktop.com/docs/howtos/customize-i3-configuration/</guid><description>How to work with Regolith 2&amp;rsquo;s defaults # The default configurations are stored in /usr/share/regolith/i3/config.d. These are loaded alphabetically. Then user configurations in ~/.config/regolith2/i3/config.d are loaded, also in alphabetical order. Regolith&amp;rsquo;s default configuration is built to be customized by setting Xresources variables, adding user configuration, and adding or removing default configurations via apt. For this reason, there are several approaches to customization of i3 in Regolith that can be used separately or in combination to achieve your configuration cleanly:</description></item><item><title>Keybindings</title><link>https://regolith-desktop.com/docs/reference/keybindings/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://regolith-desktop.com/docs/reference/keybindings/</guid><description>Action Key Binding Launch - Application ⊞ Win Space Launch - Browser ⊞ Win Shift Enter Launch - Command ⊞ Win Shift Space Launch - File Browser ⊞ Win Shift n Launch - File Search ⊞ Win Alt Space Launch - Notification Viewer ⊞ Win n Launch - Terminal ⊞ Win Enter Launch - This Dialog ⊞ Win Shift ?</description></item><item><title>Package URL change for 2.1</title><link>https://regolith-desktop.com/posts/repo-url-change-2.1/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://regolith-desktop.com/posts/repo-url-change-2.1/</guid><description>Summary # For the Regolith 2.1 release, the host name of the URL from which apt pulls packages has changed. The new hostname is regolith-desktop.org. In order to update to Regolith 2.1 and get fixes and upgrades going forward kindly update your apt configuration.
The old apt URL:
/etc/apt/sources.list.d/regolith.list:
deb [arch=amd64 signed-by=/usr/share/keyrings/regolith-archive-keyring.gpg] https://regolith-desktop.io/release-ubuntu-jammy-amd64 testing main ^ | (this changes to '.org') The new apt URL:
/etc/apt/sources.list.d/regolith.list:
deb [arch=amd64 signed-by=/usr/share/keyrings/regolith-archive-keyring.gpg] https://regolith-desktop.</description></item><item><title>Config Files</title><link>https://regolith-desktop.com/docs/reference/configurations/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://regolith-desktop.com/docs/reference/configurations/</guid><description>Config file quick reference # Component Default Config User Config Notes i3 / i3-gaps /etc/regolith/i3/config, /usr/share/regolith/i3/config.d ~/.config/regolith2/i3 Extend Regolith2 config by creating config.d and partials in the user config dir, or globally override it by creating config. More Xresources /usr/share/regolith-look/default ~/.config/regolith2/Xresources ~/.Xresources is also loaded but intended for properties that may also be required in other desktop sessions. More Bar status indicators /usr/share/i3xrocks/conf.</description></item><item><title>3.0 Release Notes</title><link>https://regolith-desktop.com/docs/reference/Releases/regolith-3.0-release-notes/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://regolith-desktop.com/docs/reference/Releases/regolith-3.0-release-notes/</guid><description>Regolith 3.0 is in pre-release. This document currently describes beta 2 and will be updated up to the final release once available. For wayland support, the XResource key names were changed as to not be tied to i3-wm. See the migration guide below for details on how to update customizations. Regolith 3.0 is a major release focusing on a new Wayland-based session, Debian 12, and Ubuntu 23.04 support.</description></item><item><title>Basic Usage</title><link>https://regolith-desktop.com/docs/using-regolith/basics/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://regolith-desktop.com/docs/using-regolith/basics/</guid><description>Usage # Launch an Application # After the first login, the screen will contain a bar at the bottom and some keyboard shortcuts in a dialog. This dialog, ilia, provides assistance for finding keybindings for various actions in the desktop environment. It may be dismissed with the esc key and invoked again with super shift ? . To launch an application, press super space and a similar dialog will load with the applications installed on the system.</description></item><item><title>2.2 Release Notes</title><link>https://regolith-desktop.com/docs/reference/Releases/regolith-2.2-release-notes/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://regolith-desktop.com/docs/reference/Releases/regolith-2.2-release-notes/</guid><description>Regolith 2.2 is a minor release focusing on bug fixes and Ubuntu 22.10 support.
New Features # Ubuntu 22.10 (kinetic) support Wallpaper may be changed in regolith-control-center on Ubuntu Kinetic and Debian Bookworm. Bug Fixes # i3-swap-focus now available as released in 2.1 Numerous fixes and polish added to ilia Known Issues # No localization for ilia Changelog Delta from Regolith Desktop 2.</description></item><item><title>Configuration</title><link>https://regolith-desktop.com/docs/using-regolith/configuration/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://regolith-desktop.com/docs/using-regolith/configuration/</guid><description>Recommended Packages for New Users # Looks # Install all of the official Regolith looks:
sudo apt install regolith-look-* Alternatively, apt will list available looks that may be installed:
apt list | grep regolith-look- NOTE: this may pull in fonts, themes, and wallpapers. For users looking to minimize disk usage, uninstalling looks that are unused is recommended.
See below for details on how to select a look.
Status Indicators # The following snippet installs status indicator packages recommended for new users:</description></item><item><title>2.1 Release Notes</title><link>https://regolith-desktop.com/docs/reference/Releases/regolith-2.1-release-notes/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://regolith-desktop.com/docs/reference/Releases/regolith-2.1-release-notes/</guid><description>Regolith 2.1 is a minor release including several improvements, bug fixes, and optimizations.
New Features # Regolith Linux 2.1 ISOs (based from Ubuntu 22.04) Looks dracula, ayu, ayu-dark, ayu-mirage, i3-default, and lascaille added Looks can be loaded from user directories (~/.config/regolith2/looks) i3-swap-focus is now available. Navigate to last window with keybinding &amp;lt;super&amp;gt; . Bug Fixes # Ilia&amp;rsquo;s file search dialog was broken on Jammy, this has been fixed PtrSc hotkeys working as in 1.</description></item><item><title>2.0 Release Notes</title><link>https://regolith-desktop.com/docs/reference/Releases/regolith-2.0-release-notes/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://regolith-desktop.com/docs/reference/Releases/regolith-2.0-release-notes/</guid><description>Regolith 2.0 is a major release with some breaking changes to looks and i3 configuration, and includes several improvements and optimizations.
New Features # Adding Debian Bullseye to the list of supported OS&amp;rsquo;s including Ubuntu Focal and Jammy. The desktop UI component rofi was replaced with desktop executor designed specifically for Regolith: ilia. The desktop UI component gnome-control-center was replaced with a settings app designed specifically for Regolith: regolith-control-center.</description></item><item><title>1.6 Release Notes</title><link>https://regolith-desktop.com/docs/reference/Releases/regolith-1.6.0-release-notes/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://regolith-desktop.com/docs/reference/Releases/regolith-1.6.0-release-notes/</guid><description>Regolith R1.6 is a feature release which includes several improvements and optimizations. Regolith 1.6&amp;rsquo;s primary feature is a return of the ISO installation method.
Features # Feature Screenshot Description Return of Regolith Linux ISO Up to Regolith 1.4.1, we hand-built each ISO for major version releases. This became too brittle and time intensive, and so work began on build automation to generate the ISO.</description></item><item><title>Xresources</title><link>https://regolith-desktop.com/docs/reference/xresources/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://regolith-desktop.com/docs/reference/xresources/</guid><description>Xresources Key Description gtk.theme_name GTK Theme gtk.icon_theme_name GTK Icon Theme gnome.terminal.audible-bell Enables audible bell in gnome-terminal (true / false) gtk.document_font_name GTK Document Font Name gtk.font_name General purpose font for GTK apps and the desktop gtk.monospace_font_name Font for monospace areas such as i3bar and the terminal gnome.terminal.background-transparency-percent Background transparency value for gnome-terminal (0 - 100).</description></item><item><title>1.5.3 Release Notes</title><link>https://regolith-desktop.com/docs/reference/Releases/regolith-1.5.3-release-notes/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://regolith-desktop.com/docs/reference/Releases/regolith-1.5.3-release-notes/</guid><description>Regolith 1.5.3 is a bug fix release. The following list contains brief descriptions of fixes and updates per package since the Regolith 1.5.2 release:
Release Notes for i3xrocks # i3xrocks (1.3.5-1) bionic; urgency=medium
[ Ken Gilmer ]
Do not print system file error if user files do not exist. Addresses https://github.com/regolith-linux/regolith-i3xrocks-config/issues/114. Release Notes for regolith-desktop # regolith-desktop (2.111-1bionic) bionic; urgency=medium
[ Ken Gilmer ]
Move from i3xrocks-todo to regolith-todo to address https://github.</description></item><item><title>1.5.2 Release Notes</title><link>https://regolith-desktop.com/docs/reference/Releases/regolith-1.5.2-release-notes/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://regolith-desktop.com/docs/reference/Releases/regolith-1.5.2-release-notes/</guid><description>Regolith 1.5.2 is a bug fix release. The following list contains brief descriptions of fixes and updates per package since the Regolith 1.5.1 release:
Release Notes for regolith-compositor-picom-glx # Remove manual fade flag passed to compositor in favor of specification in config file. Allows users to specify fade parameters via config file. Release Notes for regolith-ftue # Check update flag before changing gnome-terminal. Allows users to turn gnome-terminal profile generation off.</description></item><item><title>1.5.1 Release Notes</title><link>https://regolith-desktop.com/docs/reference/Releases/regolith-1.5.1-release-notes/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://regolith-desktop.com/docs/reference/Releases/regolith-1.5.1-release-notes/</guid><description>Regolith 1.5.1 is a bug fix release. The following list contains brief descriptions of fixes and updates per package since the Regolith 1.5 release:
Release Notes for i3-next-workspace # Initial copy from regolith-i3xrocks-config. Release Notes for regolith-compositor-picom-glx # Add xrender-sync-fence for better support of nvidia systems. Release Notes for regolith-default-settings # Add breaks declaration to deal w/ ISO upgrade issue Release Notes for regolith-desktop # ship version file with all desktop variants Update version to 1.</description></item><item><title>1.5 Release Notes</title><link>https://regolith-desktop.com/docs/reference/Releases/regolith-1.5-release-notes/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://regolith-desktop.com/docs/reference/Releases/regolith-1.5-release-notes/</guid><description>Regolith R1.5 is a feature release which includes several improvements and optimizations. To summarize, Regolith 1.5 ships simpler workspace management, a Rofi-based Look switcher, and numerous internal optimizations and cleanup. Read below for more details.
Features # Feature Screenshot Description Next Free Workspace A typical part of managing workspaces in an i3-based desktop is moving to unused workspaces and then loading some applications.</description></item><item><title>1.4.1 Release Notes</title><link>https://regolith-desktop.com/docs/reference/Releases/regolith-1.4.1-release-notes/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://regolith-desktop.com/docs/reference/Releases/regolith-1.4.1-release-notes/</guid><description>Regolith R1.4.1 is a fast follow up to 1.4 that fixes a few serious bugs, detailed on the mailing list. In addition to the package updates, a new boot animation is provided by the package plymouth-theme-regolith that is installed by default on the ISO. The ISO also now excludes a deprecated touchpad driver that was conflicting with Settings. Existing PPA-based installations can simply get the updates via their typical package update process.</description></item><item><title>1.4 Release Notes</title><link>https://regolith-desktop.com/docs/reference/Releases/regolith-1.4-release-notes/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://regolith-desktop.com/docs/reference/Releases/regolith-1.4-release-notes/</guid><description>Regolith R1.4 is a major feature release which includes several improvements and optimizations. Regolith is now smaller and more efficient. The ISO-based installer is now based from the Xubuntu image, and moves from the gdm3 display manager to LightDM. This allows for less resource consumption at runtime and dramatically smaller download size1. A new look, lascaille and file search dialog round out the major new features. Read below for more details.</description></item><item><title>1.3.1 Release Notes</title><link>https://regolith-desktop.com/docs/reference/Releases/regolith-1.3.1-release-notes/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://regolith-desktop.com/docs/reference/Releases/regolith-1.3.1-release-notes/</guid><description>R1.3.1 is a quick followup to R1.3 that adds polish and usability features. Headlining features include a more concise way of overriding Xresource defaults and several enhancements to the Remontoire keybinding viewer.
If you maintain your own i3 config file, note that the copy shipped in Regolith 1.3.1 has changed in that the comment format has been modified to be readable by Remontoire (example). Without updating your copy i3 config comments, you will not see any keybindings.</description></item><item><title>1.3 Release Notes</title><link>https://regolith-desktop.com/docs/reference/Releases/regolith-1.3-release-notes/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://regolith-desktop.com/docs/reference/Releases/regolith-1.3-release-notes/</guid><description>Following R1.2, the 1.3 release focused on usability issues reported by users and a continuing refinement of the desktop environment in general, with a focus on making the system easier for those inexperienced with tiling window managers.
Features # Feature Screenshot Description Cahuella GTK Theme A new GTK theme was created for Regolith that more closely follows the standard GNOME theme, Adwaita.</description></item><item><title>Looking for Translators</title><link>https://regolith-desktop.com/posts/localization/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://regolith-desktop.com/posts/localization/</guid><description>With the 2.0 release out the door, we&amp;rsquo;re looking for help to translate the index page and the &amp;ldquo;using regolith&amp;rdquo; section into languages other than English. In the past we&amp;rsquo;ve used a translation system, but it turned out to be too complex for many people to understand. For the Regolith 2.0 site we&amp;rsquo;ll rely on Hugo&amp;rsquo;s multilingual support.
For a given language translation the following files must be translated:
content/_index.md content/docs/using-regolith/basics.</description></item><item><title>Build System</title><link>https://regolith-desktop.com/docs/reference/build-system/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://regolith-desktop.com/docs/reference/build-system/</guid><description>Overview # This page describes how packages are generate from source code, and how those packages combine to actualize the Regolith desktop environment. This document covers Regolith only and does not intend to describe upstream dependencies, general package manager concepts, or other aspects of build systems.
Terms # Distro - Short for distribution, in the context of this document, may be considered a variation of a Linux-based OS operating system.</description></item><item><title>Announcing Regolith 2</title><link>https://regolith-desktop.com/posts/announce-regolith-2/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://regolith-desktop.com/posts/announce-regolith-2/</guid><description>Introduction # Regolith 2 is the next major release of the Regolith Desktop environment. Here is a summary of the big changes in the release:
Use i3 or i3-gaps interchangeably Simplify the loading of Xresources, discovery, and management of looks Support for i3 config partials, allowing for safer and richer extension capabilities Provide a package topography necessary for future changes including alternative sessions and backends Debian Bullseye support, along with Ubuntu Focal and Jammy Move to new custom desktop executor ilia from rofi for app and command launching, notifications, and more Regolith 1.</description></item><item><title>Thanks to</title><link>https://regolith-desktop.com/posts/attribution/</link><pubDate>Sat, 18 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://regolith-desktop.com/posts/attribution/</guid><description>The Regolith Desktop exists as an integration of many open source projects and a little bit of glue code and some unique desktop components. The Regolith project is built upon many projects.
The following projects in particular deserve special mention:
The i3 community, including Michael Stapelberg and Ingo Bürk. The Rofi community, including Dave Davenport. Picom, an actively maintained desktop compositor, including yshui. The Gnome Flashback project, supported by Alberts Muktupāvels and Dmitry Shachnev.</description></item><item><title>Foundations for Regolith on Wayland (GSoC'22)</title><link>https://regolith-desktop.com/posts/sway_integration_gsoc/</link><pubDate>Sun, 25 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://regolith-desktop.com/posts/sway_integration_gsoc/</guid><description>Introduction # Regolith is a modern desktop environment designed to let you work faster by reducing unnecessary clutter and ceremony. It offers a keyboard based workflow and a tiling window manager that allows efficient management of windows, monitors and workspaces. Built on top of Ubuntu, GNOME Flashback, and i3, Regolith stands on a well-supported and consistent foundation.
In its current implementation, the use i3 window manager binds Regolith to X11.</description></item><item><title>Assign a workspace to a specific Output (Display)</title><link>https://regolith-desktop.com/docs/howtos/workspace-on-output/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://regolith-desktop.com/docs/howtos/workspace-on-output/</guid><description>NOTICE: This page was copied from the Regolith 1.x website and has not been updated for Regolith 2. It may contain out of date information. In order to configure i3 to assign a workspace to a given monitor, first find the device name for the monitor you wish to use with xrandr:
$ xrandr --listmonitors Monitors: 1 0: +*eDP-1 1920/309x1080/173+0+0 eDP-1 In this case, the output name is eDP-1. Next add a line like this into a staged copy of your i3 config file:</description></item><item><title>Change Bar Status indicators</title><link>https://regolith-desktop.com/docs/howtos/add-remove-blocklets/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://regolith-desktop.com/docs/howtos/add-remove-blocklets/</guid><description>Adding or Removing status indicators # Finding Status Indicators # $ apt search i3xrocks- Installing a Status Indicator # $ sudo apt install i3xrocks-memory $ regolith-look refresh Customization of the i3 bar # Each status indicator on the bar is managed by a file. The name of the file maps to the position of the status indicator on the bar, e.g. a file&amp;rsquo;s name starting with 10_ mean its corresponding indicator will be positioned before an indicator which has a configuration file starting with 20_.</description></item><item><title>Change Notification Systems</title><link>https://regolith-desktop.com/docs/howtos/replace-notification-system/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://regolith-desktop.com/docs/howtos/replace-notification-system/</guid><description>NOTICE: This page was copied from the Regolith 1.x website and has not been updated for Regolith 2. It may contain out of date information. Regolith ships with a notification system called Rofication. It is designed to work in the background and not use pop-ups as a way of alerting the user to a new notification. Rather, a small bar item displays the current number of unread notifications and a dialog can activated to interact with the content of the current notifications.</description></item><item><title>Change the Bar Date and Time Format</title><link>https://regolith-desktop.com/docs/howtos/time-format/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://regolith-desktop.com/docs/howtos/time-format/</guid><description>NOTICE: This page was copied from the Regolith 1.x website and has not been updated for Regolith 2. It may contain out of date information. The time format (12 or 24 hour) can be specified in Settings:
The date format can be specified by selecting the appropriate region in Settings. A preview of the date format is provided, and logging back in is required for changes to take effect.</description></item><item><title>Change the Default Terminal</title><link>https://regolith-desktop.com/docs/howtos/change-terminal/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://regolith-desktop.com/docs/howtos/change-terminal/</guid><description>The default terminal that ships with Regolith R1.4 is gnome-terminal, but any X terminal emulator can be used. To update Regolith to use your already installed terminal of your choice, use update-alternatives to specify it as default:
Run update-alternatives --config x-terminal-emulator to see all available terminals installed on your system. Select the terminal you prefer.</description></item><item><title>Change the Default Window Gap</title><link>https://regolith-desktop.com/docs/howtos/default-gap/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://regolith-desktop.com/docs/howtos/default-gap/</guid><description>Like most configuration in Regolith, the i3-gaps gap size can be tuned via Xresources (See here for all Xresource definitions).
Create or add the following value to your ~/.config/regolith2/Xresources file: i3-wm.gaps.inner.size: 20 In this example we&amp;rsquo;re setting the default gap to 20 pixels.
Reload the Xresources configuration: $ regolith-look refresh Further Reading # See the reference page for configurations for more details about config files in Regolith.</description></item><item><title>Change the lock screen program</title><link>https://regolith-desktop.com/docs/howtos/change-lockscreen/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://regolith-desktop.com/docs/howtos/change-lockscreen/</guid><description>1. Configure gnome-flashback to Disable Built-in Lockscreen # By default gnome-flashback handles the lock screen for Regolith. This can be adjusted by modifying it&amp;rsquo;s configuration via the gsettings command line program:
$ gsettings set org.gnome.gnome-flashback screensaver false 2. Cause Your Lock screen program to Run from i3 Keybinding # Specify the following override line in your ~/.config/regolith2/Xresources file (substituting your-script.sh with the command you wish to use for the locking your screen):</description></item><item><title>Change the Terminal Font Size</title><link>https://regolith-desktop.com/docs/howtos/terminal-font/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://regolith-desktop.com/docs/howtos/terminal-font/</guid><description>NOTICE: This page was copied from the Regolith 1.x website and has not been updated for Regolith 2. It may contain out of date information. Create or add the following value to your ~/.config/regolith2/Xresources file: gnome.terminal.font: JetBrains Mono 14 Reload the Xresources configuration: $ regolith-look refresh Open a new terminal to see the change take effect.</description></item><item><title>Change Workspace Icons and Labels</title><link>https://regolith-desktop.com/docs/howtos/change-workspace-icons/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://regolith-desktop.com/docs/howtos/change-workspace-icons/</guid><description>NOTICE: This page was copied from the Regolith 1.x website and has not been updated for Regolith 2. It may contain out of date information. Adding icons to workspaces can give your desktop a nice and functional look.
Finding icons # Icons are actually characters from fonts installed by Regolith looks. Each look comes with a specific icon font. The icon font is defined in the typeface_bar variable in the typeface config file.</description></item><item><title>Disable Mouse Hiding (unclutter)</title><link>https://regolith-desktop.com/docs/howtos/disable-unclutter/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://regolith-desktop.com/docs/howtos/disable-unclutter/</guid><description>NOTICE: This page was copied from the Regolith 1.x website and has not been updated for Regolith 2. It may contain out of date information. By default the mouse cursor disappears if unused for a few seconds. If you prefer that the mouse cursor always remains visible on the screen, follow these steps:
Specify an empty value for the unclutter launcher program with an Xresources override: $ echo &amp;quot;i3-wm.</description></item><item><title>Find and Install Packages</title><link>https://regolith-desktop.com/docs/howtos/find-install-packages/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://regolith-desktop.com/docs/howtos/find-install-packages/</guid><description>NOTICE: This page was copied from the Regolith 1.x website and has not been updated for Regolith 2. It may contain out of date information. Regolith is a Debian-based system. Debian packaging tools can be used to find and install packages.
Find package via the command line # The apt command can be used to query installed or all packages:
$ apt list --installed &amp;lt;package name&amp;gt; # finds installed packages $ apt list &amp;lt;package name&amp;gt; # finds all packages For example, to list all official Regolith looks that could be installed, run:</description></item><item><title>Customize Compositor</title><link>https://regolith-desktop.com/docs/howtos/customize-compositor/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://regolith-desktop.com/docs/howtos/customize-compositor/</guid><description>How to customize your compositor (visual effects) # Pay special attention to this section if you are experiencing odd visual glitches or slow graphics performance. A compositor is a UI component that applies visual effects to windows before they are rendered on-screen. Many desktop environments integrate a compositor directly into the window manager, making it difficult to switch out or disable. In Regolith, the compositor is defined as a pluggable “extension point” in the packaging system.</description></item><item><title>How to Hide i3-bar by default</title><link>https://regolith-desktop.com/docs/howtos/hide-i3-bar-by-default/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://regolith-desktop.com/docs/howtos/hide-i3-bar-by-default/</guid><description>NOTICE: This page was copied from the Regolith 1.x website and has not been updated for Regolith 2. It may contain out of date information. Add the line
i3-wm.bar.mode: hide to $HOME/.config/regolith2/Xresources file. The next time you log in the bar should be hidden by default.</description></item><item><title>Install the Sway Compositor</title><link>https://regolith-desktop.com/docs/howtos/install-sway/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://regolith-desktop.com/docs/howtos/install-sway/</guid><description>To install the wayland session, follow these steps:
Install the regolith-session-sway package and it&amp;rsquo;s dependencies. Reboot Select &amp;ldquo;Regolith on Wayland&amp;rdquo; session in the login panel Hardware Support # Those using proprietary nvidia drivers for their graphics cards must set regolith.sway.unsupported_gpu: true in their XResources. This is not an issue with the open source drivers nouveau. See more here.
Bar Changes # The wayland session uses i3status-rs rather than i3xrocks.</description></item><item><title>Launch an app in a Floating Window</title><link>https://regolith-desktop.com/docs/howtos/floating-window/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://regolith-desktop.com/docs/howtos/floating-window/</guid><description>NOTICE: This page was copied from the Regolith 1.x website and has not been updated for Regolith 2. It may contain out of date information. Most X11 applications support a flag --class to specify the class under which the application runs. Regolith is configured such that apps with a class of floating_window will launch with i3&amp;rsquo;s floating window mode.
Examples # gnome-terminal # Launch the terminal in floating mode:</description></item><item><title>Launch Default i3 Session</title><link>https://regolith-desktop.com/docs/howtos/vanilla-i3-gaps/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://regolith-desktop.com/docs/howtos/vanilla-i3-gaps/</guid><description>NOTICE: This page was copied from the Regolith 1.x website and has not been updated for Regolith 2. It may contain out of date information. To do so on Ubuntu, run sudo apt install i3-gaps-session to add an option on login that starts vanilla i3-gaps without regolith.
Use Case # This is useful for, say, running an application that does not integrate well with GNOME. For example, Spotify&amp;rsquo;s unmaintained official Linux client mishandles its file selection dialogue and crashes when</description></item><item><title>Manage a To-Do List</title><link>https://regolith-desktop.com/docs/howtos/tdcli-blocklet/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://regolith-desktop.com/docs/howtos/tdcli-blocklet/</guid><description>NOTICE: This page was copied from the Regolith 1.x website and has not been updated for Regolith 2. It may contain out of date information. td-cli is a command line todo manager written in Python3 for organizing todo lists across multiple projects.
Regolith includes a status bar blocklet for accessing td-cli directly from the bar. It can be installed as follows:
sudo apt install i3xrocks-todo After installing td-cli you can access it via command line using td.</description></item><item><title>Minimal Ubuntu Install</title><link>https://regolith-desktop.com/docs/howtos/minimal-ubuntu-install/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://regolith-desktop.com/docs/howtos/minimal-ubuntu-install/</guid><description>This page describes how to install the Regolith Desktop into Ubuntu Server. This approach produces a minimal setup as many of the standard GNOME desktop packages present in a desktop install will be avoided.
Steps # 1. Install Ubuntu Server # Follow online instructions for installing a fresh copy of Ubuntu Server versions either 20.04 or 22.04.
2. Add Regolith&amp;rsquo;s package key and apt repository # Once Ubuntu Server has been installed, log into a terminal session.</description></item><item><title>Override Xresources</title><link>https://regolith-desktop.com/docs/howtos/override-xres/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://regolith-desktop.com/docs/howtos/override-xres/</guid><description>Regolith relies on the Xresources system to provide a consolidated interface configuration. By changing Xresources values, Regolith can be customized in ways such as updating the user interface, specifying custom behaviors, or defining a specific format for some of the blocklets on the bar.
In Regolith, Xresources values can be changed via two methods: supplying your own Xresources files, and overriding the existing Xresources values. The latter approach is strongly recommended, as it makes upgrading to newer versions of Regolith less likely to break your customizations.</description></item><item><title>Remove Unneeded Dependencies</title><link>https://regolith-desktop.com/docs/howtos/remove-unneeded-deps/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://regolith-desktop.com/docs/howtos/remove-unneeded-deps/</guid><description>When Regolith is installed via ISO, only the necessary desktop components or packages are installed by default. However when installing Regolith into an existing Ubuntu system, some desktop components that Regolith does not require will still be installed on the system. There is nothing wrong with keeping these additional packages, in fact they are important if you wish to switch back to the default Ubuntu session at some point, however some users prefer to remove them.</description></item><item><title>Stage Config Files</title><link>https://regolith-desktop.com/docs/howtos/stage-configs/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://regolith-desktop.com/docs/howtos/stage-configs/</guid><description>If you only wish to override or provide new Xresources values, staging configs is not required and not recommended. Overriding Xresources value is described in a separate article. Regolith uses a number of configuration files to determine the behavior and look of various components. While it&amp;rsquo;s possible to simply edit these files directly, users who do so run the risk of having their configurations overwritten upon future updates. The Debian packaging system should ask users if they wish to take updates or keep the existing files, but this may have unintended side effects if users take partial updates of files.</description></item><item><title>Support Multiple Batteries</title><link>https://regolith-desktop.com/docs/howtos/multiple-batteries/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://regolith-desktop.com/docs/howtos/multiple-batteries/</guid><description>NOTICE: This page was copied from the Regolith 1.x website and has not been updated for Regolith 2. It may contain out of date information. Out of the box the primary battery status will be displayed in the i3-bar. For some laptops that have multiple batteries, e.g. ThinkPads, you want to have both batteries displayed:
Stage your i3xrocks configuration files, then open ~/.config/regolith2/i3xrocks/conf.d/80_battery in your editor of choice. Find the line that pertains to the battery blocklet: # Battery indicator # # Displays total percentage charge left of specified battery.</description></item><item><title>Verify behavior against upstream</title><link>https://regolith-desktop.com/docs/howtos/gnome-flashback-session/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://regolith-desktop.com/docs/howtos/gnome-flashback-session/</guid><description>NOTICE: This page was copied from the Regolith 1.x website and has not been updated for Regolith 2. It may contain out of date information. Regolith is composed of several existing open-source projects plus some additional custom packages. Sometimes when a bug is found in Regolith, actually it&amp;rsquo;s a bug in an upstream project. Determining the source of bugs is a first step in getting them fixed.
Check gnome-flashback # Most of Regolith&amp;rsquo;s GNOME support comes from the gnome-flashback project.</description></item></channel></rss>