<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Using Regolith on Regolith Desktop</title><link>https://regolith-desktop.com/docs/using-regolith/</link><description>Recent content in Using Regolith on Regolith Desktop</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><atom:link href="https://regolith-desktop.com/docs/using-regolith/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>First Launch</title><link>https://regolith-desktop.com/docs/using-regolith/first-launch/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://regolith-desktop.com/docs/using-regolith/first-launch/</guid><description>First Launch # Regolith&amp;rsquo;s default interface lacks any visual hint as to how to launch applications or perform other common tasks. This can make the first time experience a bit confusing. However using the Regolith interface is relatively simple by only committing the following two keybindings to memory:
Action Keybinding Keybinding Viewer super shift ? App Launcher super space The Super Key # Most keybindings you&amp;rsquo;ll be using with Regolith start with the super key.</description></item><item><title>Basic Usage</title><link>https://regolith-desktop.com/docs/using-regolith/basics/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://regolith-desktop.com/docs/using-regolith/basics/</guid><description>Basic Usage # While we&amp;rsquo;ll cover everything in greater detail in other areas of the documentation, this page covers basic usage of Regolith.
The Super Key # Most keybindings you&amp;rsquo;ll be using with Regolith start with the super key. This key typically says &amp;ldquo;WIN&amp;rdquo; or has a MS Windows logo on it. On a Mac it is the Command ⌘ key. Going forward, this key will simply be referred to as super but keep in mind that you can change which physical button super maps to in your configuration if you choose to.</description></item><item><title>Configuration</title><link>https://regolith-desktop.com/docs/using-regolith/configuration/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://regolith-desktop.com/docs/using-regolith/configuration/</guid><description>Configuration # Wallpaper # The wallpaper can be changed via the Settings app, or super c , by going to the Background tab and selecting the preferred image.
Wallpaper can also be set via dotfiles for those that prefer file-based configuration management. This can be done by specifying the path to the wallpaper image via the Xresources key gnome.wallpaper.
Regardless of which style you prefer, you can refer to the more extensive documentation for additional details.</description></item></channel></rss>