<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Using Regolith on Regolith Desktop</title><link>https://regolith-desktop.com/docs/using-regolith/</link><description>Recent content in Using Regolith on Regolith Desktop</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><atom:link href="https://regolith-desktop.com/docs/using-regolith/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>First Launch</title><link>https://regolith-desktop.com/docs/using-regolith/first-launch/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://regolith-desktop.com/docs/using-regolith/first-launch/</guid><description>First Launch # Regolith&amp;rsquo;s default interface lacks any visual hint as to how to launch applications or perform other common tasks. This can make the first time experience a bit confusing. However using the Regolith interface is relatively simple by only committing the following two keybindings to memory:
Action Keybinding Purpose Keybinding Viewer super shift ? View and execute available keybindings App Launcher super space Launch a desktop application The Super Key # Most keybindings you&amp;rsquo;ll be using with Regolith start with the super key.</description></item><item><title>Basic Usage</title><link>https://regolith-desktop.com/docs/using-regolith/basics/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://regolith-desktop.com/docs/using-regolith/basics/</guid><description>Basic Usage # While we&amp;rsquo;ll cover everything in greater detail in other areas of the documentation, this page covers basic usage of Regolith.
Launch an Application # After logging in, you&amp;rsquo;ll be at a blank screen with the bar at the bottom and some keyboard shortcuts on the right. To launch an application, press super space and a menu will be presented with all of the applications installed on the system.</description></item><item><title>Configuration</title><link>https://regolith-desktop.com/docs/using-regolith/configuration/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://regolith-desktop.com/docs/using-regolith/configuration/</guid><description>Configuration # Wallpaper # Wallpaper can be set by specifying the path to the wallpaper image via the Xresources key regolith.wallpaper.file.
Example, assuming the file /usr/share/backgrounds/hardy_wallpaper_uhd.png is present:
echo &amp;quot;regolith.wallpaper.file: /usr/share/backgrounds/hardy_wallpaper_uhd.png&amp;quot; &amp;gt;&amp;gt; ~/.config/regolith2/Xresources regolith-look refresh To change the image treatment (zoom, scale, etc.) of the wallpaper image, set regolith.wallpaper.options. Options are:
“none” “wallpaper” “centered” “scaled” “stretched” “zoom” “spanned” Example:
echo &amp;quot;regolith.wallpaper.options: zoom&amp;quot; &amp;gt;&amp;gt; ~/.config/regolith2/Xresources regolith-look refresh To specify a color rather than an image use the Xresource key regolith.</description></item></channel></rss>