<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>How To on Regolith Desktop</title><link>https://regolith-desktop.com/docs/howtos/</link><description>Recent content in How To on Regolith Desktop</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><lastBuildDate>Wed, 04 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://regolith-desktop.com/docs/howtos/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Assign a workspace to a specific Output (Display)</title><link>https://regolith-desktop.com/docs/howtos/workspace-on-output/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://regolith-desktop.com/docs/howtos/workspace-on-output/</guid><description>NOTICE: This page was copied from the Regolith 1.x website and has not been updated for Regolith 2. It may contain out of date information. In order to configure i3 to assign a workspace to a given monitor, first find the device name for the monitor you wish to use with xrandr:
$ xrandr --listmonitors Monitors: 1 0: +*eDP-1 1920/309x1080/173+0+0 eDP-1 In this case, the output name is eDP-1. Next add a line like this into a staged copy of your i3 config file:</description></item><item><title>Change Bar Status indicators</title><link>https://regolith-desktop.com/docs/howtos/add-remove-blocklets/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://regolith-desktop.com/docs/howtos/add-remove-blocklets/</guid><description>Adding or Removing status indicators # Finding Status Indicators # $ apt search i3xrocks- Installing a Status Indicator # $ sudo apt install i3xrocks-memory $ regolith-look refresh Customization of the i3 bar # Each status indicator on the bar is managed by a file. The name of the file maps to the position of the status indicator on the bar, e.g. a file&amp;rsquo;s name starting with 10_ mean its corresponding indicator will be positioned before an indicator which has a configuration file starting with 20_.</description></item><item><title>Change Notification Systems</title><link>https://regolith-desktop.com/docs/howtos/replace-notification-system/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://regolith-desktop.com/docs/howtos/replace-notification-system/</guid><description>NOTICE: This page was copied from the Regolith 1.x website and has not been updated for Regolith 2. It may contain out of date information. Regolith ships with a notification system called Rofication. It is designed to work in the background and not use pop-ups as a way of alerting the user to a new notification. Rather, a small bar item displays the current number of unread notifications and a dialog can activated to interact with the content of the current notifications.</description></item><item><title>Change the Bar Date and Time Format</title><link>https://regolith-desktop.com/docs/howtos/time-format/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://regolith-desktop.com/docs/howtos/time-format/</guid><description>NOTICE: This page was copied from the Regolith 1.x website and has not been updated for Regolith 2. It may contain out of date information. The time format (12 or 24 hour) can be specified in Settings:
The date format can be specified by selecting the appropriate region in Settings. A preview of the date format is provided, and logging back in is required for changes to take effect.</description></item><item><title>Change the Default Terminal</title><link>https://regolith-desktop.com/docs/howtos/change-terminal/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://regolith-desktop.com/docs/howtos/change-terminal/</guid><description>The default terminal that ships with Regolith R1.4 is gnome-terminal, but any X terminal emulator can be used. To update Regolith to use your already installed terminal of your choice, use update-alternatives to specify it as default:
Run update-alternatives --config x-terminal-emulator to see all available terminals installed on your system. Select the terminal you prefer.</description></item><item><title>Change the Default Window Gap</title><link>https://regolith-desktop.com/docs/howtos/default-gap/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://regolith-desktop.com/docs/howtos/default-gap/</guid><description>Like most configuration in Regolith, the i3-gaps gap size can be tuned via Xresources (See here for all Xresource definitions).
Create or add the following value to your ~/.config/regolith2/Xresources file: i3-wm.gaps.inner.size: 20 In this example we&amp;rsquo;re setting the default gap to 20 pixels.
Reload the Xresources configuration: $ regolith-look refresh Further Reading # See the reference page for configurations for more details about config files in Regolith.</description></item><item><title>Change the lock screen program</title><link>https://regolith-desktop.com/docs/howtos/change-lockscreen/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://regolith-desktop.com/docs/howtos/change-lockscreen/</guid><description>1. Configure gnome-flashback to Disable Built-in Lockscreen # By default gnome-flashback handles the lock screen for Regolith. This can be adjusted by modifying it&amp;rsquo;s configuration via the gsettings command line program:
$ gsettings set org.gnome.gnome-flashback screensaver false 2. Cause Your Lock screen program to Run from i3 Keybinding # Specify the following override line in your ~/.config/regolith2/Xresources file (substituting your-script.sh with the command you wish to use for the locking your screen):</description></item><item><title>Change the Terminal Font Size</title><link>https://regolith-desktop.com/docs/howtos/terminal-font/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://regolith-desktop.com/docs/howtos/terminal-font/</guid><description>NOTICE: This page was copied from the Regolith 1.x website and has not been updated for Regolith 2. It may contain out of date information. Create or add the following value to your ~/.config/regolith2/Xresources file: gnome.terminal.font: JetBrains Mono 14 Reload the Xresources configuration: $ regolith-look refresh Open a new terminal to see the change take effect.</description></item><item><title>Change Workspace Icons and Labels</title><link>https://regolith-desktop.com/docs/howtos/change-workspace-icons/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://regolith-desktop.com/docs/howtos/change-workspace-icons/</guid><description>NOTICE: This page was copied from the Regolith 1.x website and has not been updated for Regolith 2. It may contain out of date information. Adding icons to workspaces can give your desktop a nice and functional look.
Finding icons # Icons are actually characters from fonts installed by Regolith looks. Each look comes with a specific icon font. The icon font is defined in the typeface_bar variable in the typeface config file.</description></item><item><title>Disable Mouse Hiding (unclutter)</title><link>https://regolith-desktop.com/docs/howtos/disable-unclutter/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://regolith-desktop.com/docs/howtos/disable-unclutter/</guid><description>NOTICE: This page was copied from the Regolith 1.x website and has not been updated for Regolith 2. It may contain out of date information. By default the mouse cursor disappears if unused for a few seconds. If you prefer that the mouse cursor always remains visible on the screen, follow these steps:
Specify an empty value for the unclutter launcher program with an Xresources override: $ echo &amp;quot;i3-wm.</description></item><item><title>Find and Install Packages</title><link>https://regolith-desktop.com/docs/howtos/find-install-packages/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://regolith-desktop.com/docs/howtos/find-install-packages/</guid><description>NOTICE: This page was copied from the Regolith 1.x website and has not been updated for Regolith 2. It may contain out of date information. Regolith is a Debian-based system. Debian packaging tools can be used to find and install packages.
Find package via the command line # The apt command can be used to query installed or all packages:
$ apt list --installed &amp;lt;package name&amp;gt; # finds installed packages $ apt list &amp;lt;package name&amp;gt; # finds all packages For example, to list all official Regolith looks that could be installed, run:</description></item><item><title>How to Hide i3-bar by default</title><link>https://regolith-desktop.com/docs/howtos/hide-i3-bar-by-default/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://regolith-desktop.com/docs/howtos/hide-i3-bar-by-default/</guid><description>NOTICE: This page was copied from the Regolith 1.x website and has not been updated for Regolith 2. It may contain out of date information. Add the line
i3-wm.bar.mode: hide to $HOME/.config/regolith2/Xresources file. The next time you log in the bar should be hidden by default.</description></item><item><title>Launch an app in a Floating Window</title><link>https://regolith-desktop.com/docs/howtos/floating-window/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://regolith-desktop.com/docs/howtos/floating-window/</guid><description>NOTICE: This page was copied from the Regolith 1.x website and has not been updated for Regolith 2. It may contain out of date information. Most X11 applications support a flag --class to specify the class under which the application runs. Regolith is configured such that apps with a class of floating_window will launch with i3&amp;rsquo;s floating window mode.
Examples # gnome-terminal # Launch the terminal in floating mode:</description></item><item><title>Launch Default i3 Session</title><link>https://regolith-desktop.com/docs/howtos/vanilla-i3-gaps/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://regolith-desktop.com/docs/howtos/vanilla-i3-gaps/</guid><description>NOTICE: This page was copied from the Regolith 1.x website and has not been updated for Regolith 2. It may contain out of date information. To do so on Ubuntu, run sudo apt install i3-gaps-session to add an option on login that starts vanilla i3-gaps without regolith.
Use Case # This is useful for, say, running an application that does not integrate well with GNOME. For example, Spotify&amp;rsquo;s unmaintained official Linux client mishandles its file selection dialogue and crashes when</description></item><item><title>Manage a To-Do List</title><link>https://regolith-desktop.com/docs/howtos/tdcli-blocklet/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://regolith-desktop.com/docs/howtos/tdcli-blocklet/</guid><description>NOTICE: This page was copied from the Regolith 1.x website and has not been updated for Regolith 2. It may contain out of date information. td-cli is a command line todo manager written in Python3 for organizing todo lists across multiple projects.
Regolith includes a status bar blocklet for accessing td-cli directly from the bar. It can be installed as follows:
sudo apt install i3xrocks-todo After installing td-cli you can access it via command line using td.</description></item><item><title>Override Xresources</title><link>https://regolith-desktop.com/docs/howtos/override-xres/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://regolith-desktop.com/docs/howtos/override-xres/</guid><description>NOTICE: This page was copied from the Regolith 1.x website and has not been updated for Regolith 2. It may contain out of date information. Regolith relies on the Xresources system to provide a consolidated interface configuration. By changing Xresources values, Regolith can be customized in ways such as updating the user interface, specifying custom behaviors, or defining a specific format for some of the blocklets on the bar.</description></item><item><title>Remove Unneeded Dependencies</title><link>https://regolith-desktop.com/docs/howtos/remove-unneeded-deps/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://regolith-desktop.com/docs/howtos/remove-unneeded-deps/</guid><description>When Regolith is installed via ISO, only the necessary desktop components or packages are installed by default. However when installing Regolith into an existing Ubuntu system, some desktop components that Regolith does not require will still be installed on the system. There is nothing wrong with keeping these additional packages, in fact they are important if you wish to switch back to the default Ubuntu session at some point, however some users prefer to remove them.</description></item><item><title>Stage Config Files</title><link>https://regolith-desktop.com/docs/howtos/stage-configs/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://regolith-desktop.com/docs/howtos/stage-configs/</guid><description>If you only wish to override or provide new Xresources values, staging configs is not required and not recommended. Overriding Xresources value is described in a separate article. Regolith uses a number of configuration files to determine the behavior and look of various components. While it&amp;rsquo;s possible to simply edit these files directly, users who do so run the risk of having their configurations overwritten upon future updates. The Debian packaging system should ask users if they wish to take updates or keep the existing files, but this may have unintended side effects if users take partial updates of files.</description></item><item><title>Support Multiple Batteries</title><link>https://regolith-desktop.com/docs/howtos/multiple-batteries/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://regolith-desktop.com/docs/howtos/multiple-batteries/</guid><description>NOTICE: This page was copied from the Regolith 1.x website and has not been updated for Regolith 2. It may contain out of date information. Out of the box the primary battery status will be displayed in the i3-bar. For some laptops that have multiple batteries, e.g. ThinkPads, you want to have both batteries displayed:
Stage your i3xrocks configuration files, then open ~/.config/regolith2/i3xrocks/conf.d/80_battery in your editor of choice. Find the line that pertains to the battery blocklet: # Battery indicator # # Displays total percentage charge left of specified battery.</description></item><item><title>Update packages selectively</title><link>https://regolith-desktop.com/docs/howtos/install-from-unstable/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://regolith-desktop.com/docs/howtos/install-from-unstable/</guid><description>NOTICE: This page was copied from the Regolith 1.x website and has not been updated for Regolith 2. It may contain out of date information. You can enable the Regolith unstable PPA by adding it to your apt sources:
$ sudo add-apt-repository ppa:regolith-linux/unstable Selective upgrades # It is recommended that you enable selective upgrades from the unstable PPA. This can be done by configuring your apt preferences to only allow selective installs from this PPA:</description></item><item><title>Upgrade Regolith from 1.6 to 2.0</title><link>https://regolith-desktop.com/docs/howtos/upgrade-1.6-2.0/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://regolith-desktop.com/docs/howtos/upgrade-1.6-2.0/</guid><description>This page describes how to upgrade Regolith to 2.0. The general process is to remove the 1.6 packages and then install the 2.0 packages.
Ubuntu Upgrade # If updating Regolith is part of a distro upgrade process, first upgrade the distro. Once the distro upgrade is complete and is working with it&amp;rsquo;s default session, proceed with Regolith 2. The distro upgrade process will automatically remove the Regolith 1.x PPA from your system.</description></item><item><title>Verify behavior against upstream</title><link>https://regolith-desktop.com/docs/howtos/gnome-flashback-session/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://regolith-desktop.com/docs/howtos/gnome-flashback-session/</guid><description>NOTICE: This page was copied from the Regolith 1.x website and has not been updated for Regolith 2. It may contain out of date information. Regolith is composed of several existing open-source projects plus some additional custom packages. Sometimes when a bug is found in Regolith, actually it&amp;rsquo;s a bug in an upstream project. Determining the source of bugs is a first step in getting them fixed.
Check gnome-flashback # Most of Regolith&amp;rsquo;s GNOME support comes from the gnome-flashback project.</description></item><item><title>Wallpaper Configuration</title><link>https://regolith-desktop.com/docs/howtos/configure-wallpaper/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://regolith-desktop.com/docs/howtos/configure-wallpaper/</guid><description>This page describes how to configure the wallpaper in Regolith, which can be set via Xresources overrides.
Xresources # The way of setting the wallpaper is by specifying a file path to the image in the Xresources key gnome.wallpaper. Upon session load, wallpaper will be set if a image file is specified at this key. For example, here is how to specify an override to set the wallpaper to the default Ubuntu wallpaper:</description></item></channel></rss>