<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Blog on Regolith Desktop</title><link>https://regolith-desktop.com/posts/</link><description>Recent content in Blog on Regolith Desktop</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><atom:link href="https://regolith-desktop.com/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Package URL change for 2.1</title><link>https://regolith-desktop.com/posts/repo-url-change-2.1/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://regolith-desktop.com/posts/repo-url-change-2.1/</guid><description>Summary # For the Regolith 2.1 release, the host name of the URL from which apt pulls packages has changed. The new hostname is regolith-desktop.org. In order to update to Regolith 2.1 and get fixes and upgrades going forward kindly update your apt configuration.
The old apt URL:
/etc/apt/sources.list.d/regolith.list:
deb [arch=amd64 signed-by=/usr/share/keyrings/regolith-archive-keyring.gpg] https://regolith-desktop.io/release-ubuntu-jammy-amd64 testing main ^ | (this changes to '.org') The new apt URL:
/etc/apt/sources.list.d/regolith.list:
deb [arch=amd64 signed-by=/usr/share/keyrings/regolith-archive-keyring.gpg] https://regolith-desktop.</description></item><item><title>Looking for Translators</title><link>https://regolith-desktop.com/posts/localization/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://regolith-desktop.com/posts/localization/</guid><description>With the 2.0 release out the door, we&amp;rsquo;re looking for help to translate the index page and the &amp;ldquo;using regolith&amp;rdquo; section into languages other than English. In the past we&amp;rsquo;ve used a translation system, but it turned out to be too complex for many people to understand. For the Regolith 2.0 site we&amp;rsquo;ll rely on Hugo&amp;rsquo;s multilingual support.
For a given language translation the following files must be translated:
content/_index.md content/docs/using-regolith/basics.</description></item><item><title>Announcing Regolith 2</title><link>https://regolith-desktop.com/posts/announce-regolith-2/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://regolith-desktop.com/posts/announce-regolith-2/</guid><description>Introduction # Regolith 2 is the next major release of the Regolith Desktop environment. Here is a summary of the big changes in the release:
Use i3 or i3-gaps interchangeably Simplify the loading of Xresources, discovery, and management of looks Support for i3 config partials, allowing for safer and richer extension capabilities Provide a package topography necessary for future changes including alternative sessions and backends Debian Bullseye support, along with Ubuntu Focal and Jammy Move to new custom desktop executor ilia from rofi for app and command launching, notifications, and more Regolith 1.</description></item><item><title>Thanks to</title><link>https://regolith-desktop.com/posts/attribution/</link><pubDate>Sat, 18 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://regolith-desktop.com/posts/attribution/</guid><description>The Regolith Desktop exists as an integration of many open source projects and a little bit of glue code and some unique desktop components. The Regolith project is built upon many projects.
The following projects in particular deserve special mention:
The i3 community, including Michael Stapelberg and Ingo Bürk. The Rofi community, including Dave Davenport. Picom, an actively maintained desktop compositor, including yshui. The Gnome Flashback project, supported by Alberts Muktupāvels and Dmitry Shachnev.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://regolith-desktop.com/posts/sway_integration_gsoc/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://regolith-desktop.com/posts/sway_integration_gsoc/</guid><description>Introduction # Regolith is a modern desktop environment designed to let you work faster by reducing unnecessary clutter and ceremony. It offers a keyboard based workflow and a tiling window manager that allows efficient management of windows, monitors and workspaces. Built on top of Ubuntu, GNOME Flashback, and i3, Regolith stands on a well-supported and consistent foundation.
In its current implementation, the use i3 window manager binds Regolith to X11.</description></item></channel></rss>