<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Regolith Desktop – Blog</title><link>https://regolith-desktop.com/posts/</link><description>Recent content in Blog on Regolith Desktop</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><atom:link href="https://regolith-desktop.com/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Status Updates October 2024</title><link>https://regolith-desktop.com/posts/status_update_10_24/</link><pubDate>Tue, 29 Oct 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://regolith-desktop.com/posts/status_update_10_24/</guid><description>
&lt;h2>Ubuntu 24.10 (Oracular Oriole) Support&lt;span class="hx-absolute -hx-mt-20" id="ubuntu-2410-oracular-oriole-support">&lt;/span>
&lt;a href="#ubuntu-2410-oracular-oriole-support" class="subheading-anchor" aria-label="Permalink for this section">&lt;/a>&lt;/h2>&lt;p>Canonical completed their 20th Ubuntu release with Oracular this month. A beta of Regolith 3.2 is available for testing, see &lt;a href="https://github.com/orgs/regolith-linux/discussions/1073" target="_blank" rel="noopener">this discussion thread&lt;/a> for details. As this is not a new Regolith release, but rather the addition of a new Ubuntu version on Regolith 3.2, the &lt;a href="https://regolith-desktop.com/docs/reference/Releases/regolith-3.2-release-notes/" >3.2 release notes&lt;/a> continue to be the latest.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2>Ubuntu Summit 2024&lt;span class="hx-absolute -hx-mt-20" id="ubuntu-summit-2024">&lt;/span>
&lt;a href="#ubuntu-summit-2024" class="subheading-anchor" aria-label="Permalink for this section">&lt;/a>&lt;/h2>&lt;img src="https://regolith-desktop.com/images/posts/P_20241027_083737.jpg" alt="Near Huis ten Bois at Ubuntu Summit 24" title="Near Huis ten Bois at Ubuntu Summit 24" width="320" style="float: right; margin: 35px;"/>
&lt;p>I submitted a &lt;a href="https://events.canonical.com/event/51/contributions/554/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">lightning talk&lt;/a> that was accepted at &lt;a href="https://events.canonical.com/event/51/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Ubuntu Summit 2024&lt;/a> in &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Hague" target="_blank" rel="noopener">The Hague&lt;/a>, Netherlands. I was able to attend in person and while present at the conference, had a wonderful time touring around a few of the many many parks by bike. The talk itself was intended to be a simple project status update. However during the conference a number of &lt;a href="https://events.canonical.com/event/51/contributions/509/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">inspiring&lt;/a> &lt;a href="https://events.canonical.com/event/51/contributions/522/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">talks&lt;/a> motivated me to try for more. In particular, it struck me during a demo of the new Cosmic Desktop, that rarely if ever did I hear anyone discussing &lt;em>why&lt;/em> i3-like windowing environments are attractive to some users. So, I attempted to briefly explain my take during my brief talk:&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>i3-like environments (as typically configured, of course you can do whatever you like) bias towards application usage over discovery. Concretely, i3 expects a bit more of the user, to know what they want to do. In return, the system throws less distraction and minutia at the user. This, at lease in my experience, leads to longer periods of deep concentration on the problem I&amp;rsquo;m working on. In summary, the user is better able to put their attention where it matters: the application.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>Due to the short period of the talk, I didn&amp;rsquo;t have much time to get my point across, but hopefully the information was interesting to some attendees. I&amp;rsquo;m grateful for the event organizer&amp;rsquo;s continued support of the Regolith Desktop project.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2>Regolith 3.3&lt;span class="hx-absolute -hx-mt-20" id="regolith-33">&lt;/span>
&lt;a href="#regolith-33" class="subheading-anchor" aria-label="Permalink for this section">&lt;/a>&lt;/h2>&lt;p>Work continues on the next Regolith release. Highlights include:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Simplified Deb repository layout&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;code>ilia&lt;/code> module refactor&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;code>armesto&lt;/code> integration&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul></description></item><item><title>Status Updates August 2024</title><link>https://regolith-desktop.com/posts/status_update_08_24/</link><pubDate>Fri, 02 Aug 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://regolith-desktop.com/posts/status_update_08_24/</guid><description>
&lt;h2>Regolith 3.2&lt;span class="hx-absolute -hx-mt-20" id="regolith-32">&lt;/span>
&lt;a href="#regolith-32" class="subheading-anchor" aria-label="Permalink for this section">&lt;/a>&lt;/h2>&lt;p>We&amp;rsquo;re currently on beta 4 of Regolith 3.2. It&amp;rsquo;s been a longer release cycle than hoped, as many users are wanting to run Regolith on the latest Ubuntu LTS: Noble. In this release, the items that come to mind that required more time than expected were the systemd init refactoring and integration of GNOME 46. Soumya initiated the effort to clean up and make our init code generally consistent with systemd, cleaning up some rather old ad-hoc shell script init code. This refactoring covers both Sway and i3 window managers. I expect this effort to provide a more robust and consistent start up process that in turn will allow users to more easily configure and reason about the execution of their desktop setup.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We will require at least one more beta to clean up some issues encountered between X11 and Wayland sessions, as well as take in some great fixes provided by community members. But, it feels like we are almost there.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2>DebConf 24&lt;span class="hx-absolute -hx-mt-20" id="debconf-24">&lt;/span>
&lt;a href="#debconf-24" class="subheading-anchor" aria-label="Permalink for this section">&lt;/a>&lt;/h2>&lt;img src="https://regolith-desktop.com/images/posts/PXL_20240729_102150414.jpg" alt="Soumya and Ken at DebConf 24" title="Soumya and Ken at DebConf 24" width="320" style="float: right; margin: 35px;"/>
&lt;p>Due to the generous support of our financial contributors, Soumya and I were able to meet up at &lt;a href="https://debconf24.debconf.org/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">DebConf 24&lt;/a> this year in Busan, Korea. This is our second in-person conference meet up; last year Canonical graciously sponsored both of us to attend the Ubuntu Summit in Riga, Latvia. That event was incredibly productive and so we were both keen on further opportunities to collaborate in person and with the larger Debian world.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The travel costs associated with our attendance at the conference was paid from our &lt;a href="https://opencollective.com/regolith/donate" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Open Collective account&lt;/a>. While we do not spend a lot of effort to advertise or solicit financial contributions, happily there are enough people donating to the project to allow us to travel from time to time when advantageous to the project and it fits into our personal schedules. There are also a few financial contributors over the years that have contributed rather generous sums to the project. While I don&amp;rsquo;t feel it appropriate to call them out by name here, we are very happy to have received these funds to support the project.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We aim to invest all of the financial contributions back into the project such that users will receive value back in terms of better quality software, broader support, and healthy working relationships with related projects.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2>What&amp;rsquo;s Coming Next&lt;span class="hx-absolute -hx-mt-20" id="whats-coming-next">&lt;/span>
&lt;a href="#whats-coming-next" class="subheading-anchor" aria-label="Permalink for this section">&lt;/a>&lt;/h2>&lt;h3>Debian Project Integration&lt;span class="hx-absolute -hx-mt-20" id="debian-project-integration">&lt;/span>
&lt;a href="#debian-project-integration" class="subheading-anchor" aria-label="Permalink for this section">&lt;/a>&lt;/h3>&lt;p>Soumya has &lt;a href="https://packages.debian.org/sid/trawld" target="_blank" rel="noopener">begun the effort&lt;/a> to integrate the Wayland session into the Debian package repository. Our goal is to integrate the entire wayland session into Debian. Once there, we plan to then provide a &amp;ldquo;spin&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;flavor&amp;rdquo; to downstream Ubuntu. I hope that this will eventually result in an officially supported flavor that will enable users to install Regolith from an ISO as has been done in past LTS releases. However due to time constraints, I will not take on providing an ISO for the 24.04 release.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3>Simplified Debian Repositories&lt;span class="hx-absolute -hx-mt-20" id="simplified-debian-repositories">&lt;/span>
&lt;a href="#simplified-debian-repositories" class="subheading-anchor" aria-label="Permalink for this section">&lt;/a>&lt;/h3>&lt;p>Khosrow has been working for a number of months on an &lt;a href="https://github.com/regolith-linux/voulage/pull/38" target="_blank" rel="noopener">updated Debian apt repo setup&lt;/a>. Once this is in place, the Regolith deb repos will be far more consistent with other projects and will be easier for users to configure and reason about.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3>Armesto&lt;span class="hx-absolute -hx-mt-20" id="armesto">&lt;/span>
&lt;a href="#armesto" class="subheading-anchor" aria-label="Permalink for this section">&lt;/a>&lt;/h3>&lt;p>Work on a rust-based replacement to the &lt;a href="https://github.com/regolith-linux/armesto" target="_blank" rel="noopener">rofication daemon&lt;/a> is expected to land in the next release, in addition to the Wayland session getting a more consistent waybar configuration. This will also set the stage to enable some user-requested capabilities of notifications, such as a stronger visual indication of new notifications.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3>Ilia&lt;span class="hx-absolute -hx-mt-20" id="ilia">&lt;/span>
&lt;a href="#ilia" class="subheading-anchor" aria-label="Permalink for this section">&lt;/a>&lt;/h3>&lt;p>More work is planned to go into &lt;a href="https://github.com/regolith-linux/ilia" target="_blank" rel="noopener">&lt;code>ilia&lt;/code>&lt;/a> to modularize pages such that it is usable by any general desktop environment. The Regolith-specific logic will move to plugins provided by distinct binary packages. This will allow easier integration into Debian and provide another launcher option to the free desktop community.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Additionally I will continue to work on load performance improvements for users that experience lag in the dialog loading of applications.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2>Deprecations&lt;span class="hx-absolute -hx-mt-20" id="deprecations">&lt;/span>
&lt;a href="#deprecations" class="subheading-anchor" aria-label="Permalink for this section">&lt;/a>&lt;/h2>&lt;p>As mentioned in the 3.2 release notes, we will no longer produce packages for Debian Bullseye or any Ubuntu releases other than Jammy and Noble.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We will not provide an ISO of the 24.04 release.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2>Feedback&lt;span class="hx-absolute -hx-mt-20" id="feedback">&lt;/span>
&lt;a href="#feedback" class="subheading-anchor" aria-label="Permalink for this section">&lt;/a>&lt;/h2>&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://github.com/orgs/regolith-linux/discussions" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Feedback&lt;/a> about this status update or the Regolith project in general is always welcome.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Status Updates Nov 2023</title><link>https://regolith-desktop.com/posts/status_update_11_23/</link><pubDate>Sun, 26 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://regolith-desktop.com/posts/status_update_11_23/</guid><description>
&lt;h2>Regolith 3.1 &amp;amp; Ubuntu Mantic Support&lt;span class="hx-absolute -hx-mt-20" id="regolith-31--ubuntu-mantic-support">&lt;/span>
&lt;a href="#regolith-31--ubuntu-mantic-support" class="subheading-anchor" aria-label="Permalink for this section">&lt;/a>&lt;/h2>&lt;p>Due to an &lt;a href="https://github.com/regolith-linux/regolith-desktop/issues/936" target="_blank" rel="noopener">issue&lt;/a> associated with the Desktop Portal system and the GNOME implementation, that results in a severe usability regression, Ubuntu Mantic support has been delayed until it can be resolved. This change came into Regolith with the inclusion of GNOME 45 into Ubuntu Mantic. It looks like we&amp;rsquo;re getting some help from upstream, but it may be some time until we&amp;rsquo;re able to support GNOME 45-based distros if the solution ends up being that we need to implement our own portal backend to coexist with GNOME&amp;rsquo;s backend.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Additionally, Ubuntu 24.04 will be an LTS release and the people behind Ubuntu are putting extra work into it to ensure it&amp;rsquo;s a great one. We may end up forgoing Mantic support altogether if a short term solution does not present itself.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2>Ubuntu Summit 2023&lt;span class="hx-absolute -hx-mt-20" id="ubuntu-summit-2023">&lt;/span>
&lt;a href="#ubuntu-summit-2023" class="subheading-anchor" aria-label="Permalink for this section">&lt;/a>&lt;/h2>&lt;p>Soumya and I had the opportunity to travel to Riga, Latvia earlier this month to attend the &lt;a href="https://ubuntu.com/blog/ubuntu-summit-2023" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Ubuntu Summit&lt;/a>, graciously hosted by Canonical. There were a lot of great sessions and it was fantastic to reconnect with some familiar faces and collaborators from the previous year. So many brilliant and friendly people in one place!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://regolith-desktop.com/images/posts/P_20231103_185135~2.jpg" alt="" loading="lazy" />&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In particular &lt;a href="https://github.com/PapyElGringo" target="_blank" rel="noopener">PapyElGringo&lt;/a> announced a new project &lt;a href="https://github.com/free-explorers/veshell" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Veshell&lt;/a> as a successor to the &lt;a href="https://github.com/material-shell/material-shell" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Material Shell&lt;/a> project. I enjoyed learning about the spacial approach to app and workspace management, and look forward to seeing how the new project progresses.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Soumya and I attended the Ubuntu Flavor sync session and were given several helpful contacts to work with as the Regolith project gets a closer association to upstream projects Debian and Ubuntu. Stay tuned for future news on this front.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2>Chat System Migration: Slack -&amp;gt; Matrix&lt;span class="hx-absolute -hx-mt-20" id="chat-system-migration-slack---matrix">&lt;/span>
&lt;a href="#chat-system-migration-slack---matrix" class="subheading-anchor" aria-label="Permalink for this section">&lt;/a>&lt;/h2>&lt;p>Long-time Regolith contributor Leo had setup a Slack instance in the early days of the Regolith project. It was a great help and it was an effective tool for collaboration. Over time though, I and others in the project had a desire to move to an open platform. In part this is simply due to the risky nature of relying on &amp;ldquo;free&amp;rdquo; versions of commercial, proprietary platforms. Partly due to the Ubuntu&amp;rsquo;s adoption of the &lt;a href="https://matrix.org/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Matrix protocol&lt;/a> for some community collaboration, I found it to be functional and easy to use. A &lt;a href="https://matrix.to/#/#regolith-desktop:matrix.org" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Matrix &amp;ldquo;Space&amp;rdquo; for the Regolith project&lt;/a> has been setup, any everyone is welcome to join. At some point in the next month or so we&amp;rsquo;ll retire the Slack server entirely.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Foundations for Regolith on Wayland (GSoC'22)</title><link>https://regolith-desktop.com/posts/sway_integration_gsoc/</link><pubDate>Sun, 25 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://regolith-desktop.com/posts/sway_integration_gsoc/</guid><description>
&lt;h2>Introduction&lt;span class="hx-absolute -hx-mt-20" id="introduction">&lt;/span>
&lt;a href="#introduction" class="subheading-anchor" aria-label="Permalink for this section">&lt;/a>&lt;/h2>&lt;p>Regolith is a modern desktop environment designed to let you work faster by reducing unnecessary clutter and ceremony. It offers a keyboard based workflow and a tiling window manager that allows efficient management of windows, monitors and workspaces. Built on top of Ubuntu, GNOME Flashback, and i3, Regolith stands on a well-supported and consistent foundation.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In its current implementation, the use i3 window manager binds Regolith to X11. While X11 is fairly mature, it was never built for modern systems and is based on assumptions that are valid only for computers of the ’90s. Some of the issues present in X11 based window managers are low framerates, poor support for HiDPi panels, higher latency, screen tearing etc. Wayland is a display protocol that is written from scratch and aims at simplicity and extensibility Wayland has been in development for quite some time now and its implementations are now stable enough to be considered for daily usage. In fact, many desktop environments like gnome are now providing their wayland implementations as default. Sway window manager was introduced as a drop-in replacement for i3. It is based on wayland and is devoid of most of the issues present in X11 based window managers and compositors.&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Note:&lt;/strong> The work described in this post was done as part of my &lt;a href="https://summerofcode.withgoogle.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Google Summer of Code (GSoC) 2022&lt;/a> project under the organisation &lt;a href="https://ccextractor.org/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">CCExtractor&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;h2>Objective&lt;span class="hx-absolute -hx-mt-20" id="objective">&lt;/span>
&lt;a href="#objective" class="subheading-anchor" aria-label="Permalink for this section">&lt;/a>&lt;/h2>&lt;p>The project intends to achieve integration of swaywm with the regolith ecosystem. This means, compatibility with GNOME services, integration of a configuration management system, theming using regolith look and support for other extras provided by regolith in a wayland-based environment.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2>Integrating sway with regolith&lt;span class="hx-absolute -hx-mt-20" id="integrating-sway-with-regolith">&lt;/span>
&lt;a href="#integrating-sway-with-regolith" class="subheading-anchor" aria-label="Permalink for this section">&lt;/a>&lt;/h2>&lt;p>In this section, I will described everything that I did to achieve sway integration with regolith. This required modifying several existing packages as well as writing code for new scripts and binaries.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3>Porting the regolith app launcher (ilia) to wayland&lt;span class="hx-absolute -hx-mt-20" id="porting-the-regolith-app-launcher-ilia-to-wayland">&lt;/span>
&lt;a href="#porting-the-regolith-app-launcher-ilia-to-wayland" class="subheading-anchor" aria-label="Permalink for this section">&lt;/a>&lt;/h3>&lt;p>After having a discussion with Ken, we decided that the most important part of a tiling window manager setup from a user&amp;rsquo;s perspective is the app-launcher. Regolith on X11 ships with its own app launcher called &lt;code>ilia&lt;/code>. It also provides several features apart from launching apps. This includes showing keybindings, launching terminal commands, list applications and workspaces and search files just to name a few.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Ilia is written in &lt;code>vala&lt;/code> and &lt;code>GTK&lt;/code>. This means, ilia had support for wayland right out of the box. Despite this inherent compatibility, ilia seemed to crash everytime. After looking into the logs, I realised that the issue was not with &lt;code>ilia&lt;/code> but with the way &lt;code>wayland roots&lt;/code> (wlr) handles windows that need to be ignored by the compositor. Turns out, wlr provides an extension to the wayland protocols called &lt;code>wlr-layer-shell&lt;/code> in order to handle panels and other applications that need to be positioned automatically. A client implementation of this protocol for GTK based applications is provided by the library &lt;code>gtk-layer-shell&lt;/code>. To maintain support for both &lt;code>X11&lt;/code> and &lt;code>wayland&lt;/code>, I check the &lt;code>XDG_SESSION_TYPE&lt;/code> environment variable and use gtk-layer-shell library only if the session type is wayland.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Currently, the wayland compatible version of &lt;code>ilia&lt;/code> is not packaged and exists in a &lt;a href="https://github.com/regolith-linux/ilia/tree/ubuntu/jammy-wayland" target="_blank" rel="noopener">seperate branch&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3>Trawl - A backend agnostic configuration manager&lt;span class="hx-absolute -hx-mt-20" id="trawl---a-backend-agnostic-configuration-manager">&lt;/span>
&lt;a href="#trawl---a-backend-agnostic-configuration-manager" class="subheading-anchor" aria-label="Permalink for this section">&lt;/a>&lt;/h3>&lt;p>&lt;code>Wayland&lt;/code> lacks support for &lt;code>Xresources&lt;/code> natively and requires the use &lt;code>XWayland&lt;/code>. This might not be desirable as it forces users to enable &lt;code>Xwayland&lt;/code> forcing them to be a part of a legacy ecosystem. This is the reason why we decided to create a display backend agnostic configuration manager that can be used by various applications. To maintain compatibility with the existing regolith ecosystem it was crutial to replicate the format and functionaility XResources as much as possible. &lt;code>Trawl&lt;/code> is a file based configuration management system written in rust that tries to fulfill these requirements.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://github.com/regolith-linux/trawl" target="_blank" rel="noopener">&lt;code>Trawl&lt;/code>&lt;/a> is comprised of two parts - Configuration Daemon (&lt;code>trawld&lt;/code>) and Trawl Client (&lt;code>trawldb&lt;/code>). For IPC, it uses the &lt;code>DBus&lt;/code> specification, which allows other applications to access &lt;code>trawl&lt;/code> resources with ease. In fact, trawl comes with libraries for &lt;a href="https://github.com/regolith-linux/libtrawldb" target="_blank" rel="noopener">C&lt;/a> and &lt;a href="https://crates.io/crates/trawldb" target="_blank" rel="noopener">rust&lt;/a> that make interaction with trawl clients hassle free. Trawl also tries to replicate most of the features provided by &lt;code>Xresources&lt;/code> by replicating the functionality available using the &lt;code>xrdb&lt;/code> CLI.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3>Sway - adding the set_from_resource command&lt;span class="hx-absolute -hx-mt-20" id="sway---adding-the-set_from_resource-command">&lt;/span>
&lt;a href="#sway---adding-the-set_from_resource-command" class="subheading-anchor" aria-label="Permalink for this section">&lt;/a>&lt;/h3>&lt;p>&lt;code>Sway&lt;/code> aims to be a drop in alternative for &lt;code>i3&lt;/code>. But there are some features which make sense only within the &lt;code>X11&lt;/code> ecosystem, and one such feature is the &lt;code>set_from_resource&lt;/code> command in the configs. This command allows users to set variables within the i3 configurations by querying &lt;code>XResources&lt;/code> for specific keys. Due to the lack of &lt;code>XResources&lt;/code> alternatives that are display backend agnostic, the creators of sway decided &lt;a href="https://github.com/swaywm/sway/issues/2336#issuecomment-469041201" target="_blank" rel="noopener">not to implement it&lt;/a>, even if its at the cost of breaking compatibility with i3 configurations.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Regolith relies heavily on &lt;code>XResources&lt;/code> based configurations. This helps acheive functional configurations to some extent, such that you can replicate your window manager setup just by copying over your &lt;code>XResources&lt;/code> and &lt;code>config partials&lt;/code>. In order to maintain a consistent experience across the board, it was absolutely crutial to re-implement &lt;code>set_from_resource&lt;/code> for sway.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I created a fork of sway called &lt;a href="https://github.com/regolith-linux/sway-regolith" target="_blank" rel="noopener">&lt;code>sway-regolith&lt;/code>&lt;/a> which adds the &lt;a href="https://github.com/regolith-linux/sway-regolith/blob/7d4bca923950db19bc3341d960ed5862339eb1b7/sway/commands.c#L87" target="_blank" rel="noopener">&lt;code>set_from_resource&lt;/code>&lt;/a> command. In order to communicate with the trawl demon, I used the wrapper functions provided by the &lt;a href="https://github.com/regolith-linux/libtrawldb" target="_blank" rel="noopener">&lt;code>libtrawldb&lt;/code>&lt;/a> library, which provides several wrapper functions for the DBus methods. Finally, I renamed the &lt;code>sway&lt;/code> binary to &lt;code>sway-regolith&lt;/code> in order to allow the fork and the upstream versions of sway to co-exist.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3>Regolith-displayd&lt;span class="hx-absolute -hx-mt-20" id="regolith-displayd">&lt;/span>
&lt;a href="#regolith-displayd" class="subheading-anchor" aria-label="Permalink for this section">&lt;/a>&lt;/h3>&lt;p>In regolith, the de facto way for managing and changing settings is the use of &lt;code>gnome-control-center&lt;/code>. Since the displays are managed by &lt;code>X11&lt;/code> in both &lt;code>i3&lt;/code> and &lt;code>Gnome on X11&lt;/code>, the display panel of &lt;code>gnome-control-center&lt;/code> works right out of the box. However, in the case of wayland based compositors and window managers like &lt;code>sway&lt;/code> and &lt;code>mutter&lt;/code> on wayland, the diplays are managed by the compositor itself. So &lt;code>gnome-control-center&lt;/code> can manage displays only when mutter is the compositor in use.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>On looking into &lt;code>gnome-control-center&lt;/code>&amp;rsquo;s codebase, I discovered that the display settings are applied by communicating with the &lt;code>org.mutter.DisplayConfig&lt;/code> DBus interface. So I created &lt;a href="https://github.com/regolith-linux/regolith-displayd" target="_blank" rel="noopener">&lt;code>regolith-displayd&lt;/code>&lt;/a>, which creates a &lt;code>DBus&lt;/code> interface with the same name. It primarily provides two DBus methods - &lt;code>GetCurrentState&lt;/code> and &lt;code>ApplyMonitorsConfig&lt;/code>. The &lt;code>GetCurrentState&lt;/code> method gets the current configuration of monitors and maps it into a format understandable by &lt;code>gnome-control-center&lt;/code>. Similarly, calls to the &lt;code>ApplyMonitorsConfig&lt;/code> method applies the display settings changes made from &lt;code>gnome-control-center&lt;/code> by mapping them into a format understandable by the IPC interface of sway.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;code>regolith-displayd&lt;/code> also polls the sway IPC interface to check for changes in display configuration. If a change is detected, the &lt;code>MonitorsChanged&lt;/code> signal is emmitted. &lt;code>gnome-control-center&lt;/code> reacts to this message by making a call to &lt;code>GetCurrentState&lt;/code>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In order to achieve display configuration persistance, &lt;code>regolith-displayd&lt;/code> generates &lt;code>kanshi&lt;/code> profiles based on the displays that are currently in use. These configurations are then automatically applied whenever the same monitors are connected.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3>Regolith-session&lt;span class="hx-absolute -hx-mt-20" id="regolith-session">&lt;/span>
&lt;a href="#regolith-session" class="subheading-anchor" aria-label="Permalink for this section">&lt;/a>&lt;/h3>&lt;p>&lt;code>regolith-session&lt;/code> package is probably the most important part of regolith as it essentially ties i3 with GNOME flashback. This package is also partly responsible for the &lt;code>regolith-look&lt;/code> related functionality. The code for wayland version of the package can be found in the &lt;a href="https://github.com/regolith-linux/regolith-session/tree/wayland-dev" target="_blank" rel="noopener">&lt;code>wayland-dev&lt;/code>&lt;/a> branch.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Migrating regolith-session to wayland required work on the following sections.&lt;/p>
&lt;h4>Session initialization script (&lt;code>regolith-session-wayland&lt;/code>)&lt;span class="hx-absolute -hx-mt-20" id="session-initialization-script-regolith-session-wayland">&lt;/span>
&lt;a href="#session-initialization-script-regolith-session-wayland" class="subheading-anchor" aria-label="Permalink for this section">&lt;/a>&lt;/h4>&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://github.com/regolith-linux/regolith-session/blob/c92813f5c836443ab0d85eb4e925a3aa2bbbfd2e/usr/bin/regolith-session-wayland" target="_blank" rel="noopener">This&lt;/a> script is responsible for loading the &lt;code>trawl&lt;/code> resources set by the user, loading current look information, reformatting pango markup for workspace names, registering the session with &lt;code>gnome session manager&lt;/code> and launching sway with the regolith configuration file.&lt;/p>
&lt;h4>&lt;code>/usr/share/applications/regolith-wayland.desktop&lt;/code>&lt;span class="hx-absolute -hx-mt-20" id="usrshareapplicationsregolith-waylanddesktop">&lt;/span>
&lt;a href="#usrshareapplicationsregolith-waylanddesktop" class="subheading-anchor" aria-label="Permalink for this section">&lt;/a>&lt;/h4>&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://github.com/regolith-linux/regolith-session/blob/c92813f5c836443ab0d85eb4e925a3aa2bbbfd2e/usr/share/applications/regolith-wayland.desktop" target="_blank" rel="noopener">This&lt;/a> application file executes the &lt;code>regolith-session-wayland&lt;/code> script. This application file will be read by &lt;code>gnome-session-binary&lt;/code> while loading the Required Components from the session file.&lt;/p>
&lt;h4>&lt;code>/usr/share/gnome-session/sessions/regolith-wayland.session&lt;/code>&lt;span class="hx-absolute -hx-mt-20" id="usrsharegnome-sessionsessionsregolith-waylandsession">&lt;/span>
&lt;a href="#usrsharegnome-sessionsessionsregolith-waylandsession" class="subheading-anchor" aria-label="Permalink for this section">&lt;/a>&lt;/h4>&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://github.com/regolith-linux/regolith-session/blob/c92813f5c836443ab0d85eb4e925a3aa2bbbfd2e/usr/share/gnome-session/sessions/regolith-wayland.session" target="_blank" rel="noopener">This&lt;/a> file lists out the components required by the session in order to work correctly. If all the required components cannot be loaded, the session ends abruptly with an error. Most of these components are &lt;code>gnome-settings-daemon&lt;/code> plugins. If the session is loaded using &lt;code>gnome-session --builtin&lt;/code>, it launches the required components using their respective application files instead of launching their systemd services. The &lt;code>regolith-sway&lt;/code> desktop file is also included in the required components section which launches ultimately starts the regolith session.&lt;/p>
&lt;h4>&lt;code>/usr/share/wayland-sessions/regolith-sway.dektop&lt;/code>&lt;span class="hx-absolute -hx-mt-20" id="usrsharewayland-sessionsregolith-swaydektop">&lt;/span>
&lt;a href="#usrsharewayland-sessionsregolith-swaydektop" class="subheading-anchor" aria-label="Permalink for this section">&lt;/a>&lt;/h4>&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://github.com/regolith-linux/regolith-session/blob/c92813f5c836443ab0d85eb4e925a3aa2bbbfd2e/usr/share/wayland-sessions/regolith-sway.desktop" target="_blank" rel="noopener">This&lt;/a> file is read by the display manager / login manager and shows the entry &lt;code>Regolith on Wayland&lt;/code> in the login screen. The command &lt;code>/usr/bin/gnome-session --builtin --session=regolith-wayland&lt;/code> is executed as soon as you login. This command looks for &lt;code>/usr/share/gnome-session/sessions/regolith-wayland.session&lt;/code> and loads the required components.&lt;/p>
&lt;h4>&lt;code>/usr/lib/regolith/regolith-session-common.sh&lt;/code>&lt;span class="hx-absolute -hx-mt-20" id="usrlibregolithregolith-session-commonsh">&lt;/span>
&lt;a href="#usrlibregolithregolith-session-commonsh" class="subheading-anchor" aria-label="Permalink for this section">&lt;/a>&lt;/h4>&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://github.com/regolith-linux/regolith-session/blob/c92813f5c836443ab0d85eb4e925a3aa2bbbfd2e/usr/lib/regolith/regolith-session-common.sh" target="_blank" rel="noopener">This&lt;/a> provides functionality that is used in multiple scripts (related to both &lt;code>X11&lt;/code> and &lt;code>wayland&lt;/code> based sessions). It also contains some variables that are required by many of the scripts related to &lt;code>regolith-session&lt;/code>. I&amp;rsquo;ve added several functions and environment variables that are required to provide functionality equivalent to what is provided by Regolith on X11 sessions.&lt;/p>
&lt;h4>Regolith look script (&lt;code>/usr/bin/regolith-look&lt;/code>)&lt;span class="hx-absolute -hx-mt-20" id="regolith-look-script-usrbinregolith-look">&lt;/span>
&lt;a href="#regolith-look-script-usrbinregolith-look" class="subheading-anchor" aria-label="Permalink for this section">&lt;/a>&lt;/h4>&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://github.com/regolith-linux/regolith-session/blob/c92813f5c836443ab0d85eb4e925a3aa2bbbfd2e/usr/bin/regolith-look" target="_blank" rel="noopener">This&lt;/a> provides theming related functionallity, which is one of the defining features of the regolith ecosystem. I&amp;rsquo;ve added a check to determine if the current session type (X11 or Wayland). If the current session is wayland, &lt;code>trawlcat&lt;/code> is used instead of &lt;code>xrescat&lt;/code> and &lt;code>swaymsg reload&lt;/code> is used instead of &lt;code>i3-msg refresh&lt;/code>. When loading a look, if the current session is wayland, the configurations are loaded into &lt;code>trawl&lt;/code> and if the session is X11, the resources are loaded using &lt;code>xrdb&lt;/code> as XResources.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3>Regolith Look&lt;span class="hx-absolute -hx-mt-20" id="regolith-look">&lt;/span>
&lt;a href="#regolith-look" class="subheading-anchor" aria-label="Permalink for this section">&lt;/a>&lt;/h3>&lt;p>The functionality of the &lt;code>regolith-look&lt;/code> script (located at &lt;code>/usr/bin/regolith-look&lt;/code>) has been discussed in the &lt;a href="#regolith-look-script-usrbinregolith-look" >previous section&lt;/a>. In order to apply the theme, a loader script is required. This can either be provided by the look or the user. If no loader is provided, the &lt;a href="https://github.com/regolith-linux/regolith-look-default/blob/1d50b0797c579b239664a8a96aaf7de399f0f2da/usr/share/regolith-look/default_loader.sh" target="_blank" rel="noopener">default loader script&lt;/a> (present in the &lt;code>regolith-look-default&lt;/code> package) is used. To make this loader script compatible with &lt;code>trawl&lt;/code> in wayland, I had to check if the current session is wayland and set the &lt;code>RESOURCE_GETTER&lt;/code> variable to &lt;code>trawlcat&lt;/code> accordingly.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Regolith also uses gnome-terminal by default. So in order to provide terminal theming in wayland, the &lt;a href="https://github.com/regolith-linux/regolith-ftue/blob/2b2c1a9d73e93ebc67640876839ed853130f0e8e/regolith-init-term-profile" target="_blank" rel="noopener">&lt;code>regolith-init-term-profile&lt;/code>&lt;/a> script also needs to use &lt;code>trawlcat&lt;/code> as resource getter. This script is responsible for changing the terminal profile theme.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3>Regolith-inputd&lt;span class="hx-absolute -hx-mt-20" id="regolith-inputd">&lt;/span>
&lt;a href="#regolith-inputd" class="subheading-anchor" aria-label="Permalink for this section">&lt;/a>&lt;/h3>&lt;p>Similar to outut management, input management in wayland is also dependent on the compositor. This is the reason why changing input settings from &lt;code>gnome-control-center&lt;/code> doesn&amp;rsquo;t work out of the box. In order to get the input panel of gnome-control-center to work, I created &lt;a href="https://github.com/regolith-linux/regolith-inputd" target="_blank" rel="noopener">&lt;code>regolith-inputd&lt;/code>&lt;/a>, which monitors the &lt;code>gsettings&lt;/code> schema &lt;a href="https://github.com/regolith-linux/regolith-inputd/blob/78349e1c9a77e4edcffbe5c245f8c58e138f90ea/org.gnome.desktop.peripherals.gschema.xml" target="_blank" rel="noopener">&lt;code>org.gnome.desktop.peripherals&lt;/code>&lt;/a>. This allows to map changes in input properties to sway configuration commands which are then applied using the &lt;code>sway&lt;/code> IPC interface.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2>What&amp;rsquo;s next?&lt;span class="hx-absolute -hx-mt-20" id="whats-next">&lt;/span>
&lt;a href="#whats-next" class="subheading-anchor" aria-label="Permalink for this section">&lt;/a>&lt;/h2>&lt;p>You can track work related sway integration in &lt;a href="https://github.com/orgs/regolith-linux/projects/8" target="_blank" rel="noopener">this&lt;/a> GitHub projects page. All contributions are more than welcome. I have really enjoyed working on this project and I plan to continue even after I&amp;rsquo;m done with the final evaluation for Google Summer of Code.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2>What doesn&amp;rsquo;t work&lt;span class="hx-absolute -hx-mt-20" id="what-doesnt-work">&lt;/span>
&lt;a href="#what-doesnt-work" class="subheading-anchor" aria-label="Permalink for this section">&lt;/a>&lt;/h2>&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Lock Screen (Alternatives - swaylock)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>GNOME OSD overlays (Alternatives - wob)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>GNOME flashback / gnome-shell-related stuff&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Using any Display Manager other than GDM 3 causes issues&lt;/li>
&lt;li>swaybar status (requires several reloads to work properly)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>ilia keybindings page&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;code>gnome-session-quit&lt;/code> popup&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul></description></item><item><title>Package URL change for 2.1</title><link>https://regolith-desktop.com/posts/repo-url-change-2.1/</link><pubDate>Thu, 04 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://regolith-desktop.com/posts/repo-url-change-2.1/</guid><description>
&lt;h2>Summary&lt;span class="hx-absolute -hx-mt-20" id="summary">&lt;/span>
&lt;a href="#summary" class="subheading-anchor" aria-label="Permalink for this section">&lt;/a>&lt;/h2>&lt;p>For the Regolith 2.1 release, the host name of the URL from which &lt;code>apt&lt;/code> pulls packages has changed. The new hostname is &lt;code>regolith-desktop.org&lt;/code>. In order to update to Regolith 2.1 and get fixes and upgrades going forward kindly update your apt configuration.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The old &lt;code>apt&lt;/code> URL:&lt;/p>
&lt;div class="hextra-code-block hx-relative hx-mt-6 first:hx-mt-0 hx-group/code">
&lt;div class="filename not-prose" dir="auto">/etc/apt/sources.list.d/regolith.list&lt;/div>&lt;div>&lt;div class="highlight">&lt;pre tabindex="0" class="chroma">&lt;code class="language-text" data-lang="text">&lt;span class="line">&lt;span class="cl">deb [arch=amd64 signed-by=/usr/share/keyrings/regolith-archive-keyring.gpg] https://regolith-desktop.io/release-ubuntu-jammy-amd64 testing main
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span class="line">&lt;span class="cl"> ^
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span class="line">&lt;span class="cl"> |
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span class="line">&lt;span class="cl"> (this changes to &amp;#39;.org&amp;#39;)&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>&lt;/div>&lt;/div>&lt;div class="hextra-code-copy-btn-container hx-opacity-0 hx-transition group-hover/code:hx-opacity-100 hx-flex hx-gap-1 hx-absolute hx-m-[11px] hx-right-0 hx-top-8">
&lt;button
class="hextra-code-copy-btn hx-group/copybtn hx-transition-all active:hx-opacity-50 hx-bg-primary-700/5 hx-border hx-border-black/5 hx-text-gray-600 hover:hx-text-gray-900 hx-rounded-md hx-p-1.5 dark:hx-bg-primary-300/10 dark:hx-border-white/10 dark:hx-text-gray-400 dark:hover:hx-text-gray-50"
title="Copy code"
>
&lt;div class="copy-icon group-[.copied]/copybtn:hx-hidden hx-pointer-events-none hx-h-4 hx-w-4">&lt;/div>
&lt;div class="success-icon hx-hidden group-[.copied]/copybtn:hx-block hx-pointer-events-none hx-h-4 hx-w-4">&lt;/div>
&lt;/button>
&lt;/div>
&lt;/div>
&lt;p>The new &lt;code>apt&lt;/code> URL:&lt;/p>
&lt;div class="hextra-code-block hx-relative hx-mt-6 first:hx-mt-0 hx-group/code">
&lt;div class="filename not-prose" dir="auto">/etc/apt/sources.list.d/regolith.list&lt;/div>&lt;div>&lt;div class="highlight">&lt;pre tabindex="0" class="chroma">&lt;code class="language-text" data-lang="text">&lt;span class="line">&lt;span class="cl">deb [arch=amd64 signed-by=/usr/share/keyrings/regolith-archive-keyring.gpg] https://regolith-desktop.org/release-ubuntu-jammy-amd64 testing main&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>&lt;/div>&lt;/div>&lt;div class="hextra-code-copy-btn-container hx-opacity-0 hx-transition group-hover/code:hx-opacity-100 hx-flex hx-gap-1 hx-absolute hx-m-[11px] hx-right-0 hx-top-8">
&lt;button
class="hextra-code-copy-btn hx-group/copybtn hx-transition-all active:hx-opacity-50 hx-bg-primary-700/5 hx-border hx-border-black/5 hx-text-gray-600 hover:hx-text-gray-900 hx-rounded-md hx-p-1.5 dark:hx-bg-primary-300/10 dark:hx-border-white/10 dark:hx-text-gray-400 dark:hover:hx-text-gray-50"
title="Copy code"
>
&lt;div class="copy-icon group-[.copied]/copybtn:hx-hidden hx-pointer-events-none hx-h-4 hx-w-4">&lt;/div>
&lt;div class="success-icon hx-hidden group-[.copied]/copybtn:hx-block hx-pointer-events-none hx-h-4 hx-w-4">&lt;/div>
&lt;/button>
&lt;/div>
&lt;/div>
&lt;p>All other aspects of the package configuration remain the same including the key used to verify packages.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2>Additional Info&lt;span class="hx-absolute -hx-mt-20" id="additional-info">&lt;/span>
&lt;a href="#additional-info" class="subheading-anchor" aria-label="Permalink for this section">&lt;/a>&lt;/h2>&lt;p>The Regolith 2.1 release reintroduced the ISO form of distribution. In order to generate the ISO with the production &lt;code>apt&lt;/code> URL the packages needed to be published first. This essentially required a way of publishing the release before we wish users to get access to the packages. In order to achieve this the idea of using a URL and switching the host seemed like a good idea. Problems occurred when the realities of TLS cert management became apparent. When the domain was remapped to the new host, the TLS certificates were not. Later, when the problem became known, the hosting provider gave advice on how to resolve the problem. However, the original source domain name (&lt;code>regolith-desktop.io&lt;/code>) somehow is not able to take a new cert registration from the new host. Some remedies have been suggested by users, but due to the nature of the production host we opted to leave the system as-is and migrate to the new domain to prevent further churn for users.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>When the 2.1 release was published, the URL was updated to &lt;code>regolith-desktop.org&lt;/code>. Users still using &lt;code>regolith-desktop.io&lt;/code> will most likely be stuck on the 2.0 release unless the TLS certificate issue is ignored or in some way resolved.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Looking for Translators</title><link>https://regolith-desktop.com/posts/localization/</link><pubDate>Wed, 22 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://regolith-desktop.com/posts/localization/</guid><description>
&lt;p>With the 2.0 release out the door, we&amp;rsquo;re looking for help to translate the index page and the &amp;ldquo;using regolith&amp;rdquo; section into languages other than English. In the past we&amp;rsquo;ve used a translation system, but it turned out to be too complex for many people to understand. For the &lt;a href="https://github.com/regolith-linux/regolith-desktop-website" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Regolith 2.0 site&lt;/a> we&amp;rsquo;ll rely on &lt;a href="https://gohugo.io/content-management/multilingual/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Hugo&amp;rsquo;s multilingual support&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>For a given language translation the following files must be translated:&lt;/p>
&lt;div class="hextra-code-block hx-relative hx-mt-6 first:hx-mt-0 hx-group/code">
&lt;div>&lt;div class="highlight">&lt;pre tabindex="0" class="chroma">&lt;code class="language-text" data-lang="text">&lt;span class="line">&lt;span class="cl">content/_index.md
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span class="line">&lt;span class="cl">content/docs/using-regolith/basics.md
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span class="line">&lt;span class="cl">content/docs/using-regolith/configuration.md
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span class="line">&lt;span class="cl">content/docs/using-regolith/first-launch.md&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>&lt;/div>&lt;/div>&lt;div class="hextra-code-copy-btn-container hx-opacity-0 hx-transition group-hover/code:hx-opacity-100 hx-flex hx-gap-1 hx-absolute hx-m-[11px] hx-right-0 hx-top-0">
&lt;button
class="hextra-code-copy-btn hx-group/copybtn hx-transition-all active:hx-opacity-50 hx-bg-primary-700/5 hx-border hx-border-black/5 hx-text-gray-600 hover:hx-text-gray-900 hx-rounded-md hx-p-1.5 dark:hx-bg-primary-300/10 dark:hx-border-white/10 dark:hx-text-gray-400 dark:hover:hx-text-gray-50"
title="Copy code"
>
&lt;div class="copy-icon group-[.copied]/copybtn:hx-hidden hx-pointer-events-none hx-h-4 hx-w-4">&lt;/div>
&lt;div class="success-icon hx-hidden group-[.copied]/copybtn:hx-block hx-pointer-events-none hx-h-4 hx-w-4">&lt;/div>
&lt;/button>
&lt;/div>
&lt;/div>
&lt;p>To provide a translation, simply copy the English file and add the &lt;a href="https://lingohub.com/academy/best-practices/iso-639-1-list" target="_blank" rel="noopener">two-letter language code&lt;/a> to the end of the filename. Once the translation is complete, create a pull request and we&amp;rsquo;ll merge your translation. This allows other people to read about Regolith with your language translation.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>As an example, if a Japanese translation was provided, the following new files would be added to the PR:&lt;/p>
&lt;div class="hextra-code-block hx-relative hx-mt-6 first:hx-mt-0 hx-group/code">
&lt;div>&lt;div class="highlight">&lt;pre tabindex="0" class="chroma">&lt;code class="language-text" data-lang="text">&lt;span class="line">&lt;span class="cl">content/_index.ja.md
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span class="line">&lt;span class="cl">content/docs/using-regolith/basics.ja.md
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span class="line">&lt;span class="cl">content/docs/using-regolith/configuration.ja.md
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span class="line">&lt;span class="cl">content/docs/using-regolith/first-launch.ja.md&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>&lt;/div>&lt;/div>&lt;div class="hextra-code-copy-btn-container hx-opacity-0 hx-transition group-hover/code:hx-opacity-100 hx-flex hx-gap-1 hx-absolute hx-m-[11px] hx-right-0 hx-top-0">
&lt;button
class="hextra-code-copy-btn hx-group/copybtn hx-transition-all active:hx-opacity-50 hx-bg-primary-700/5 hx-border hx-border-black/5 hx-text-gray-600 hover:hx-text-gray-900 hx-rounded-md hx-p-1.5 dark:hx-bg-primary-300/10 dark:hx-border-white/10 dark:hx-text-gray-400 dark:hover:hx-text-gray-50"
title="Copy code"
>
&lt;div class="copy-icon group-[.copied]/copybtn:hx-hidden hx-pointer-events-none hx-h-4 hx-w-4">&lt;/div>
&lt;div class="success-icon hx-hidden group-[.copied]/copybtn:hx-block hx-pointer-events-none hx-h-4 hx-w-4">&lt;/div>
&lt;/button>
&lt;/div>
&lt;/div>
&lt;p>There is some additional Hugo configuration before the translation will be available, but we can take care of that. Feel free to open an issue or reach out on &lt;a href="https://github.com/orgs/regolith-linux/discussions" target="_blank" rel="noopener">GitHub Discussions&lt;/a> with any questions, and thanks in advance!&lt;/p>
&lt;h2>Translation Workflow&lt;span class="hx-absolute -hx-mt-20" id="translation-workflow">&lt;/span>
&lt;a href="#translation-workflow" class="subheading-anchor" aria-label="Permalink for this section">&lt;/a>&lt;/h2>&lt;p>Here are some step-by-step instructions for creating a translation:&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>Create a fork of the &lt;a href="https://github.com/regolith-linux/regolith-desktop-website" target="_blank" rel="noopener">GitHub repo that contains the Regolith Desktop website&lt;/a>. (&lt;a href="https://docs.github.com/en/get-started/quickstart/fork-a-repo" target="_blank" rel="noopener">learn more&lt;/a>)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Clone the fork to your local computer.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Determine the &lt;a href="https://lingohub.com/academy/best-practices/iso-639-1-list" target="_blank" rel="noopener">two-letter designation&lt;/a> for your language.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Copy the following files to new files with the two-letter language designation (see example above).&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Translate the content to your language.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Commit and push the changes to your fork of the website repository.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Create and submit a &lt;a href="https://docs.github.com/en/pull-requests/collaborating-with-pull-requests/proposing-changes-to-your-work-with-pull-requests/about-pull-requests" target="_blank" rel="noopener">pull request&lt;/a>.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;p>By creating the pull request, Regolith project members will be notified to review and push your changes.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Announcing Regolith 2</title><link>https://regolith-desktop.com/posts/announce-regolith-2/</link><pubDate>Sat, 05 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://regolith-desktop.com/posts/announce-regolith-2/</guid><description>
&lt;h2>Introduction&lt;span class="hx-absolute -hx-mt-20" id="introduction">&lt;/span>
&lt;a href="#introduction" class="subheading-anchor" aria-label="Permalink for this section">&lt;/a>&lt;/h2>&lt;p>Regolith 2 is the next major release of the Regolith Desktop environment. Here is a summary of the big changes in the release:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Use &lt;code>i3&lt;/code> or &lt;code>i3-gaps&lt;/code> interchangeably&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Simplify the loading of Xresources, discovery, and management of looks&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Support for i3 config partials, allowing for safer and richer extension capabilities&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Provide a package topography necessary for future changes including alternative sessions and backends&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Debian Bullseye support, along with Ubuntu Focal and Jammy&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Move to new custom desktop executor &lt;code>ilia&lt;/code> from &lt;code>rofi&lt;/code> for app and command launching, notifications, and more&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>Regolith 1.6 is the end of the line for the existing Regolith desktop. The new major version 2 provides for a simplification of Regolith as a whole, with some new features as well. This upgrade will not be backwards compatible with 1.x series (but as always, users may choose to specify their own i3 config). However Regolith 2 is not radically different than the previous version. This major version bump is to allow for users to upgrade on their own schedules. As such, the 1.x package repository (PPA) will not be used for Regolith 2 packages.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2>Release Status&lt;span class="hx-absolute -hx-mt-20" id="release-status">&lt;/span>
&lt;a href="#release-status" class="subheading-anchor" aria-label="Permalink for this section">&lt;/a>&lt;/h2>&lt;p>We&amp;rsquo;re currently in pre-alpha phase of the development process. The environment is generally stable for day to day work, however because we&amp;rsquo;re reserving the right to make big changes still, using it in a production context is not recommended at this time.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2>Shipped Changes&lt;span class="hx-absolute -hx-mt-20" id="shipped-changes">&lt;/span>
&lt;a href="#shipped-changes" class="subheading-anchor" aria-label="Permalink for this section">&lt;/a>&lt;/h2>&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Convert i3 config to &lt;a href="https://github.com/i3/i3/issues/4192" target="_blank" rel="noopener">partials&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;code>conf.d&lt;/code> style Xresource discovery&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Migration from &lt;code>rofi&lt;/code> to &lt;a href="https://github.com/regolith-linux/ilia" target="_blank" rel="noopener">&lt;code>ilia&lt;/code>&lt;/a> as the desktop executor&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Migration to &lt;a href="https://www.nerdfonts.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">&lt;code>nerdfonts&lt;/code>&lt;/a> for looks to simplify and enhance font icons&lt;/li>
&lt;li>A &lt;a href="https://github.com/regolith-linux/voulage" target="_blank" rel="noopener">new build system&lt;/a> decoupled from &lt;code>launchpad.net&lt;/code> facilitating easier and more consistent distro development&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Port of looks &lt;code>lascaille&lt;/code> and &lt;code>nord&lt;/code> from the 1.x looks&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2>Changes in Development&lt;span class="hx-absolute -hx-mt-20" id="changes-in-development">&lt;/span>
&lt;a href="#changes-in-development" class="subheading-anchor" aria-label="Permalink for this section">&lt;/a>&lt;/h2>&lt;ul>
&lt;li>New website (this one!)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://github.com/regolith-linux/ilia/issues" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Polish&lt;/a> for &lt;code>ilia&lt;/code>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Bugs in wallpaper handling (gnome/dotfiles)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Better HiDPI support out of the box&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Better first time user experience&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Porting most existing looks to new Xresource schema&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Rebranding from &amp;ldquo;Regolith Linux&amp;rdquo; to &amp;ldquo;Regolith Desktop Environment&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2>Expected Release Date&lt;span class="hx-absolute -hx-mt-20" id="expected-release-date">&lt;/span>
&lt;a href="#expected-release-date" class="subheading-anchor" aria-label="Permalink for this section">&lt;/a>&lt;/h2>&lt;p>Due to the volunteer nature of the Regolith project, it&amp;rsquo;s simply not possible to a promise ship date. However, we would like to have something usable by the time of the next LTS version of Ubuntu is released, in April 2022.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2>Expected Upgrade Experience&lt;span class="hx-absolute -hx-mt-20" id="expected-upgrade-experience">&lt;/span>
&lt;a href="#expected-upgrade-experience" class="subheading-anchor" aria-label="Permalink for this section">&lt;/a>&lt;/h2>&lt;p>The Regolith 2 desktop environment will require the removal of the existing Regolith 1.x PPA and the addition of a new Debian repository. &lt;code>regolith-desktop&lt;/code> will continue to be the top-level package that provides the complete desktop environment. As before, i3 config files can be entirely controlled by users by staging a copy in their XDG user configuration directory, however with &lt;code>i3&lt;/code> &lt;code>4.20+&lt;/code>, a new option of simply providing any additional configuration via config partials is also supported.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2>Learn More&lt;span class="hx-absolute -hx-mt-20" id="learn-more">&lt;/span>
&lt;a href="#learn-more" class="subheading-anchor" aria-label="Permalink for this section">&lt;/a>&lt;/h2>&lt;p>&lt;a href="http://regolith-desktop.com/#get-regolith-20" target="_blank" rel="noopener">See here for details&lt;/a> on how to install the current pre-release version of Regolith 2, and &lt;a href="http://regolith-desktop.com/#get-regolith-20" target="_blank" rel="noopener">here for information on how you can provide feedback or contribute&lt;/a>.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Thanks to</title><link>https://regolith-desktop.com/posts/attribution/</link><pubDate>Sat, 18 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://regolith-desktop.com/posts/attribution/</guid><description>
&lt;p>The Regolith Desktop exists as an integration of many open source projects and a little bit of glue code and some unique desktop components. The Regolith project is built upon many projects.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The following projects in particular deserve special mention:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>The i3 community, including &lt;a href="https://i3wm.org">Michael Stapelberg&lt;/a> and &lt;a href="https://github.com/Airblader/i3">Ingo Bürk&lt;/a>.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>The Rofi community, including &lt;a href="https://github.com/davatorium/rofi">Dave Davenport&lt;/a>.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Picom, an actively maintained desktop compositor, including &lt;a href="https://github.com/yshui/compton">yshui&lt;/a>.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>The Gnome Flashback project, supported by &lt;a href="https://wiki.gnome.org/Projects/GnomeFlashback">Alberts Muktupāvels and Dmitry Shachnev&lt;/a>.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Other i3-GNOME integrations by &lt;a href="https://github.com/jcstr">Jesús Castro&lt;/a> and &lt;a href="https://github.com/deuill">Alex Palaistras&lt;/a>.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>The i3status community, including &lt;a href="https://github.com/vivien/i3blocks">Vivien Didelot&lt;/a>.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Design innovation by &lt;a href="https://github.com/arcticicestudio">Arctic Ice Studio&lt;/a> and &lt;a href="https://ethanschoonover.com/solarized/">Ethan Schoonover&lt;/a> and &lt;a href="https://github.com/ayu-theme">Ayu Theme&lt;/a>.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Proper nouns sourced from the fiction of &lt;a href="http://www.alastairreynolds.com/">Alastair Reynolds&lt;/a>.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>The beautiful GTK themes by &lt;a href="https://github.com/EliverLara/Nordic">Eliver Lara&lt;/a>.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Wallpapers by &lt;a href="http://wallpaper-site.webflow.io/">Psiu Puxa&lt;/a>, &lt;a href="https://unsplash.com/photos/C0OD8OM-oM0">Lucas Bellator&lt;/a>, and &lt;a href="https://unsplash.com/photos/xnqVGsbXgV4">Luca Bravo&lt;/a>.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Icons by &lt;a href="https://snwh.org/paper">Sam Hewitt&lt;/a>.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Simple and powerful build tools via the Cubic project by &lt;a href="https://launchpad.net/cubic">PJ Singh&lt;/a>.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Infrastructure by &lt;a href="https://canonical.com">Canonical&lt;/a> and &lt;a href="https://github.com">GitHub&lt;/a>.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul></description></item></channel></rss>